<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Youtube</title><link>https://konrad.website/liveboat-github-runner/</link><description></description><item><title>Who Really Built The Sphinx?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dlb44MZamw0</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Dlb44MZamw0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 22:00:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This documentary explores the controversial archaeological evidence challenging the historical accuracy of the Bible. From the "riddle of the Sphinx" - where geologists argue for a date 4,000 years earlier than traditional Egyptology - to the search for King Solomon’s lost palaces at Armageddon, we examine the artifacts, carbon dating, and ancient tunnels that are rewriting world history. Discover the scientific truth behind the legends of Jerusalem and the monumental mysteries of the ancient Middle East.

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.
Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://bit.ly/4pyExyn

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Remarkable Science of Sound | Sound Waves: The Symphony of Physics | BBC Earth Science</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zp_uXZ4hy3Y</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Zp_uXZ4hy3Y?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 18:00:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">BBC Earth Science</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Join Dr Helen Czerski as she investigates the remarkable science behind sound, with various experiments and an incredibly touching story from a woman who battled hearing loss.

Best of Earth Science: http://bit.ly/EarthLabOriginals 
Best of BBC Earth: http://bit.ly/TheBestOfBBCEarthVideos 

Taken from: Sound Waves: The Symphony of Physics (2017)

This is a channel from BBC Studios who help fund new BBC programmes. Service information and feedback: http://bbcworldwide.com/vod-feedback--contact-details.aspx]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Kiel Canal: The busiest artificial waterway in the world | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gas9GGMw2N0</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/gas9GGMw2N0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:00:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A technical masterpiece -- and a big responsibility. The Kiel Canal in Germany is the busiest artificial waterway in the world. But keeping it operational is expensive.

The infrastructure of the Kiel Canal is a much-discussed topic. As is the case in Germany with roads, bridges and railway tracks, cost-cutting measures are also impacting waterways. 

Yet the canal offers decisive advantages for freight transport: every shipping container transported here replaces a long lorry journey. This saves fuel and improves the freight’s carbon footprint.

Every year, 25,000 to 30,000 ships pass through the artificial waterway that runs between the port cities of Kiel and Brunsbüttel, connecting the Baltic Sea with the North Sea. But the Kiel Canal, which opened in 1895 and is almost 100 kilometers long, requires constant monitoring and maintenance.

In the summer of 2024, one of the large lock chambers in Brunsbüttel had to be shut down for several months, and the canal was widened. Up to 30,000 cubic meters of soil were removed here every day to meet the increased demands of shipping traffic. 

Two young boat builders, both named Paul, have little inkling of these challenges. They bought an old sailing boat and made it seaworthy again. The canal and its locks are the first big adventure of their journey, which will take them to the Canary Islands.

The impressive ships that sail the Kiel Canal have attracted their own fan base. Ship spotters regularly gather on the banks of the canal to watch the majestic cargo ships. 
Parking attendant Rainer Schmidt is in charge of maintenance for the Rendsburg viewing point. One of his most important tasks is to keep the hedges trimmed, to ensure the view of the canal is not obstructed.

The report highlights the different facets of the Kiel Canal and shows how closely people are connected to this waterway. It accompanies them in their everyday lives and during special challenges, against the impressive backdrop of an ageing, but fascinating, technical monument.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #germany #kiel 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Man Who Survived Both Atomic Bombs</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H3itdQ5Nrt0</link><author>Weird History</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/H3itdQ5Nrt0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 15:00:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCc-N24Y5OA0gqbjBwe1ttfA">Weird History</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Become a Member of Weird History! https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCc-N24Y5OA0gqbjBwe1ttfA/join

War is hell. And World War Two was inarguably one of the worst wars in history.  But what if you were at the epicenter of that trauma in a way that allowed you to witness not one… but two atomic bomb detonations… and survive? This is one incredible story of endurance!

To read more about the man who survived two atomic bomb blasts, go here:
https://www.ranker.com/list/japan-atomic-bomb-survivor-accounts/philgibbons

Be sure to subscribe to the Weird History Newsletter: https://bit.ly/WeirdHistoryNews

#abomb #survival #weirdhistory]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dying with dignity | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/yIMcufEB1Rk</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/yIMcufEB1Rk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 14:01:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In hospices, caregivers and volunteers support patients who are seriously ill and dying. They focus on quality of life and dignity in those final stages, providing a peaceful environment where people can face their last days with grace and as little fear as possible. 

What are the stories behind hospices? 

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs
______

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>&quot;I HATE GAMES as Programming Examples&quot; –@russolsen3122</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/n-FSgfkqldA</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/n-FSgfkqldA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 13:01:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out the full version on our YouTube channel now! #GOTOcon #RussOlsen #Clojure #lisplang #Agile #TDD #ChaosEngineering #FunctionalProgramming #CategoryTheory #FPvsOOP #Programming #SoftwareEngineering #TodayInTech #ViralProgrammingShorts #Viral #ViralShorts #TodayInTech #GOTO

Full version available here:
https://youtu.be/0SpsIgtOCbA

Russ Olsen - Author of "Getting Clojure" & "Eloquent Ruby" @russolsen3122 

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Russ Olsen • Getting Clojure • https://amzn.to/3J8zI8s
Russ Olsen • Eloquent Ruby • https://amzn.to/37gOhcG
Russ Olsen • Design Patterns in Ruby • https://amzn.to/3r2uBjW

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ajay Banga on India, Migration and a Youth Jobs Time Bomb | Leaders with Francine Lacqua</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IqBXFwg3fk4</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/IqBXFwg3fk4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 09:00:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Francine Lacqua sits down with Ajay Banga to discuss his journey to becoming president of the World Bank Group. From his childhood in India to a career in the private sector and eventually leading one of the world’s most influential institutions, Banga shares his leadership principles and discusses how emerging markets face a historic youth jobs gap that risks social unrest and increased migration.

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Christian Martyrs: 2,000 Years Of Faith, Persecution And Sacrifice</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jKU9IbEkBhY</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/jKU9IbEkBhY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 22:00:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[From the brutal arenas of Ancient Rome to the secret resistance movements of WW2, the act of martyrdom has shaped the course of human history. This documentary explores the visceral and often terrifying stories recorded in John Foxe’s famous "Book of Martyrs," detailing the lives of those who chose the stake, the axe, or the gallows over renouncing their convictions. We trace the evolution of sacrifice through the ages: the stoning of Saint Stephen, the political trial of Joan of Arc, the persecutions of Tudor England, and the defiant stand of Dietrich Bonhoeffer against the Nazi regime. Discover how these ultimate acts of faith became powerful tools of political and religious change, leaving a legacy that still resonates in the modern world. 

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.
Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://bit.ly/4pyExyn

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>President of the World Bank: &apos;Fail Fast&apos;</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/OJ14VmfIjHk</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/OJ14VmfIjHk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 20:00:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[“Fail fast,” says Ajay Banga, president of the World Bank. He tells Francine Lacqua that if something doesn't work, move on quickly to the next idea.

Watch the full episode of Leaders

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Opioid crisis in the US - Business &amp; addiction (2/2) | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2GLPaHa6fTs</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/2GLPaHa6fTs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 20:00:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Purdue Pharma earned billions with OxyContin. The company also triggered a race, as dozens of pharmaceutical companies rushed into the market. One was Insys, which sold fentanyl, a drug fifty times stronger than heroin.

Profit was gained by any means necessary - from strippers seducing doctors to bribery, insurance fraud and massive dose increases without the consent of patients. Some did not survive.

In Florida, unscrupulous profiteers opened pain clinics that turned out to be "pill mills” - legal hubs for drugs. Chris George, head of the largest network, cynically reports on the system that made him rich before he spent 11 years in prison.

But by the end of the 2010s, the party was over: the justice system put a stop to the legal trade. Pharmacies stopped selling opioids. But the pills did not disappear. Mexican drug cartels took over the business. Members of the Sinaloa cartel explain in the documentary how they copied the methods of US pharmaceutical companies. To this day, they continue to flood the streets of America with fentanyl.

*[Part 1: https://youtu.be/MyQQiK3vn88]*

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #opioidcrisis  #usa #addictionawareness 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Problem With Uploading Your Consciousness | Cosmic Queries #105</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p7lPFbiHwa0</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/p7lPFbiHwa0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 18:26:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Sign up for your one-dollar-per-month trial period at https://www.shopify.com/startalk 

Is your consciousness a quantum phenomenon? Is the universe one predetermined block? Neil deGrasse Tyson and cohosts Chuck Nice and Gary O’Reilly answer grab bag questions about quantum theory, the cosmological constant, and retrocausality with astrophysicist Charles Liu.

We explore a question about the Big Rip, quarks, and whether tearing the universe apart could spark a brand-new Big Bang. We break down why phantom energy would be required, what dark energy might be, and why current observations suggest the universe probably won’t rip itself to shreds even though we still don’t know what 95% of the cosmos actually is. Could the cosmological constant be changing over time?

Can light help us reconcile relativity and quantum mechanics? We discuss the work of Jacob Barandes at Harvard and whether the "duality" of light is the lynchpin to a unified theory. Are today’s mathematical tools just placeholders for physical phenomena? Questions about retrocausality, block time, and whether the universe already exists in full spark reflections on science fiction, free will, and the experiments we can’t yet perform.  Could extra dimensions provide a mathematical loophole for the laws of physics?

We confront quantum consciousness head-on. Is consciousness rooted in quantum mechanics? Could it persist beyond physical change or even death? We explore philosophical perspectives on Penrose’s ideas, AI consciousness, digital copies of the self, and why “I don’t know” remains the most powerful phrase in science. Along the way: pseudoscience, vaccines, human ignorance, collective behavior, spiritual experiences, and a final reminder that curiosity is what moves us forward.

Thanks to our Patrons Jules, Kelton Falls, Danielhero 11, Zaubergarden, Danilo Vieira Battistini, Brian Lacroix, Charles Baker, Matthew Krug, Chris A, Sandra Leduc, Rodney Schneider, Sir Sucknoramus, Dominik Zwahlen, Malachi Vanderpuye, Zac, Will Johnson, John DeGrey, ClumsyVirtuose, Holly Sweet, Chuck Montana, Jeffrey Holt, Stephen, Extronox, Jon, Ben Grund, Jona Smith, Christopher Zalenski, Wile E Coyote, Stephen Patterson, Amber Johnson, Cameron Clark, D. L. Brown, Maitreya Save, Samuel, John Blankenship, BridgesNotBurned, Nicholas, Katie Hoen, Mometc, Henry, Rajeev Patel, Neufin, Philip Olafsen, Kiara Barbosa, Justin Lodge, Ayaku, Rodney Long, Feeneydactyl, Holman Coates, John, Stephen Crotts, Scherzmeister, Cengiz Ozmen, Julie Cunningham, Ian, Chris Cutshall, Michael Taylor, Rahul, Ben Cruickshank, Jonathan Schneider, Masego Jacobs, Luis T. Guzmán, Ylian Arien, Kage, Doug Wilson, Kevin Talbot, Kevin Dillane, E. Hughes, BruceWayne, Paul Lopez, Aldo, Michael Sullivan, Gary Seighman, Bill M, Rajah, ScrubGhost, Trung N, Carl Kangas, Andres S., Emrys Roberts, Carson Grover, Marshall McCarty, Aaron Bailey, Allison Wilsmann, Callan Richardson, Elijah Rogers, Ismail Hamzaoui, Barrie Corp, Cezary Rzempoluch, Aaron Rodriquez, Tango66, CPhase595, LilB YT, M Hays, Keith, Rodriguez Rafael, Mary Howe, McGheezer, John Judkins, Jon Hicken, FiapoDM, and Manny for supporting us this week.

Timestamps:
00:00 - Introduction: Charles Liu
04:07 - Is There an Infinite Quark Glitch with the Big Rip?
14:56 - Is Light the Key to Joining Quantum and Relativity?
20:23 - Are We in a Predetermined Block Universe?
27:43 - Quantum Entanglement Through Other Dimensions
34:18 - Is Consciousness the Result of Quantum Physics? 
45:25 - Is There Scientific Basis for an Afterlife?
49:12 - Uploading Consciousness
58:03 - Examples of Scientific Ignorance 
01:08:11 - Chuck’s Experience Being One with the Universe

Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Venus, Cupid, Folly and Time by Agnolo Bronzino</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/gLBi9GtGXpg</link><author>Great Art Explained</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/gLBi9GtGXpg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 18:17:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCePDFpCr78_qmVtpoB1Axaw">Great Art Explained</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Painted around 1545 for the Medici court in Florence, this is one of the most unsettling images of love ever made.

The painting was likely a diplomatic gift from Cosimo I de’ Medici to the French court — possibly to Francis I. That context matters. The French court loved complex allegories, intellectual puzzles, and refined eroticism. This is a painting designed to be decoded.

Unlike Renaissance harmony (think Leonardo or Raphael) this painting feels tense, airless. There is no stable ground and Venus’ body twists unnaturally; Cupid’s leg bends at an impossible angle. Even beauty feels slightly disturbing.

And that’s the point.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What Happens When the Watchdog Is Accused of Wrongdoing?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/T-3CKcLXcuI</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/T-3CKcLXcuI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 15:00:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Malaysia’s Anti-Corruption Commission is facing allegations of corruption despite being the agency tasked with holding others accountable. The MACC has denied any wrongdoing, but the controversy may signal a deeper crisis for the government.

Watch the full story

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Worm with 4 Nobel Prizes</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/5EPPBDdhe6o</link><author>Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/5EPPBDdhe6o?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 15:00:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsXVk37bltHxD1rDPwtNM8Q">Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This tiny worm helped scientists map every cell, trace the first brain connectome, light up genes, and unlock powerful genetic tools. With four Nobel prizes linked to it, C. elegans quietly changed science forever.

#kurzgesagt
#inanutshell #kurzgesagt_inanutshell #learnwithshorts #science #nobelprize #nobelprizewinner 

Sources & further reading: 
https://sites.google.com/view/kgs-tiktok-sources

Follow us for more sciencey content! 🦆

OUR CHANNELS
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
German:        https://kgs.link/youtubeDE
Spanish:        https://kgs.link/youtubeES
French:          https://kgs.link/youtubeFR
Portuguese:  https://kgs.link/youtubePT
Arabic:           https://kgs.link/youtubeAR
Hindi:             https://kgs.link/youtubeHI
Japanese:     https://kgs.link/youtubeJA
Korean:          https://kgs.link/youtubeKO


HOW CAN YOU SUPPORT US?
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
This is how we make our living and it would be a pleasure if you support us!

Get Products designed with ❤ https://shop.kgs.link/shorts
Become a Part of kurzgesagt by joining the Patreon Bird Army 🐧  https://kgs.link/patreon  


DISCUSSIONS & SOCIAL MEDIA
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
Instagram:     https://kgs.link/instagram
TikTok:           https://kgs.link/tiktok
Reddit:            https://kgs.link/reddit
Discord:          https://kgs.link/discord
Twitter:           https://kgs.link/twitter
Bluesky:          https://kgs.link/bluesky
Facebook:      https://kgs.link/facebook
Newsletter:    https://kgs.link/newsletter


OUR VOICE
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
The Kurzgesagt voice is from 
Steve Taylor:  https://kgs.link/youtube-voice


OUR MUSIC ♬♪
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
700+ minutes of Kurzgesagt Soundtracks by Epic Mountain:

Spotify:            https://kgs.link/music-spotify
Soundcloud:   https://kgs.link/music-soundcloud
Bandcamp:     https://kgs.link/music-bandcamp
Youtube:          https://kgs.link/music-youtube
Facebook:       https://kgs.link/music-facebook]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>JB Pritzker wants to take down Trump | Today, Explained</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xcaUGZzdmaY</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/xcaUGZzdmaY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 13:01:43 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Illinois Governor JB Pritzker has a playbook for fighting back against the Trump administration, and he says it’s working. Few Democratic politicians have leaned into the fight against the Trump administration as aggressively as he has. While some blue-state leaders have tried to find a lane of compromise or quiet resistance, Pritzker has gone the other direction: signing laws to limit ICE operations in Illinois, creating an accountability commission staffed by retired federal judges, suing the federal government, and successfully blocking the deployment of federalized National Guard troops on Chicago’s streets.

Pritzker is a unique figure in Democratic politics. A billionaire heir to the Hyatt hotel fortune, he has spent tens of millions of his own dollars to push for a more progressive income tax in Illinois and has advocated for a national wealth tax — policies that would directly cost him money. He's also a Jewish Democrat who has navigated his party’s shifting positions on Israel and Gaza and is a two-term governor who has drawn some public support as a potential 2028 presidential candidate.

00:00 Intro 
01:22 The Illinois playbook against Trump 
03:23 Are Dems too timid in their pushback against Trump? 
05:07 Are our elections safe? 
06:17 Democrats and immigration 
09:27 A billionaire in favor of the wealth tax 
11:12 Is Gov. Pritzker running for president? 
14:03 Democratic missteps in the past 
15:58 Views on Israel and antisemitism
19:31 Is Gov. Pritzker on GLP-1s? 

Today, Explained publishes compelling interviews with key figures in politics and culture every Saturday. Subscribe to Vox’s YouTube channel to get them or listen wherever you get your podcasts. And new episodes of Today, Explained drop every weekday on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite listening app.

If you enjoy our reporting and want to hear more from Vox journalists, sign up for our Patreon at patreon.com/vox. Each month, our members get access to exclusive videos, livestreams, and chats with our newsroom.

Subscribe to our channel! http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on Facebook: http://goo.gl/U2g06o
Or Twitter: http://goo.gl/XFrZ5H]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Three takeaways from a conversation with Illinois Gov. JB Pritzker #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/h8sUY1XC_xE</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/h8sUY1XC_xE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 13:01:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Vox’s Astead Herndon is back in his hometown of Chicago to speak with Illinois Gov. JB Pritzker about why the Democrats lost in 2024, Pritzker’s own weight-loss journey, and everything in between.

You can watch their full interview here on YouTube. 

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Hidden Message on This Japanese Battle Flag</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/aojXuamElfo</link><author>Imperial War Museums</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/aojXuamElfo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:00:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3uAjWoLZ4bSi6qI9SjALxA">Imperial War Museums</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This video examines how a captured Japanese good‑luck flag became a powerful metaphor for the cultural divide in the Burma war.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Epstein Files: The 6 Names the DOJ Didn&apos;t Want You to See</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cvOuN5KqufE</link><author>Patrick Boyle</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/cvOuN5KqufE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 23:45:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCASM0cgfkJxQ1ICmRilfHLw">Patrick Boyle</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Get an exclusive 15% discount on Saily data plans! Use code BOYLE at checkout. Download Saily app or go to https://saily.com/boyle

The February 2026 release of unredacted Epstein files is finally revealing a stark reality: while billionaire CEOs are losing their jobs overseas within hours of being unmasked, the U.S. security apparatus is still actively covering up for the "Epstein Class." This video dives de into the congressional revelation of the "protected six," exposing the truth behind Leslie Wexner's secret $100 million settlement and the disturbing "torture video" emails that immediately toppled the CEO of DP World. We analyze why the FBI is still hiding crucial investigation files—like the 302 victim statements—while Ghislaine Maxwell receives a mysterious prison upgrade and offers conditional testimony. The names are finally out, but as this investigation proves, the cover-up is far from over.

In this video we ask who are: Les Wexner and Sultan Ahmed bin Sulayem.  Since the video was released after being questioned by The Guardian - the Department of Justice said that four of the men have no connection to Epstein whatsoever, but rather appeared in a photo lineup assembled by the southern district of New York (SDNY). https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2026/feb/13/four-men-unredacted-epstein-files-no-ties-ro-khanna

Patrick's Books:
Statistics For The Trading Floor:  https://amzn.to/3eerLA0
Derivatives For The Trading Floor:  https://amzn.to/3cjsyPF
Corporate Finance:  https://amzn.to/3fn3rvC 

Ways To Support The Channel
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/PatrickBoyleOnFinance
Buy Me a Coffee: https://www.buymeacoffee.com/patrickboyle

Visit our website: https://www.onfinance.org
Follow Patrick on Twitter Here: https://bsky.app/profile/pboyle.bsky.social

Business Inquiries ➡️ sponsors@onfinance.org

Patrick Boyle On Finance Podcast:
Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/7uhrWlDvxzy9hLoW0EYf0b
Apple: https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/patrick-boyle-on-finance/id1547740313
Google Podcasts: https://tinyurl.com/62862nve

Join this channel to support making this content:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCASM0cgfkJxQ1ICmRilfHLw/join]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Allegations of Intimidation by Malaysia’s Anti-Corruption Commission</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/rCDMJL6GRMw</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/rCDMJL6GRMw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 23:01:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A Bloomberg investigation uncovered allegations of intimidation by people questioned by Malaysia’s controversial anti-corruption commission -- claims the commission has denied.  

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Thirty Years&apos; War: The Religious Feud That Shattered Medieval Europe</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Hkgpn3dRqSM</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Hkgpn3dRqSM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 22:00:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In 1618, a celestial omen sparked the 30 Years War, a conflict so devastating it wiped out one-third of Germany's population. This documentary explores the transition from a war of religion to a struggle for global supremacy. Through the rare diary of a mercenary, the secret coded letters of painter-spy Peter Paul Rubens, and the shadow operations of the "Grey Eminence," we reveal how the first modern war shattered the old world and gave birth to the Europe we recognize today.

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.
Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://bit.ly/4pyExyn

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>NFL hall of famer on what players knew about CTE</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b8uAuTDDOGo</link><author>FRONTLINE PBS | Official</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/b8uAuTDDOGo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 21:00:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3ScyryU9Oy9Wse3a8OAmYQ">FRONTLINE PBS | Official</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Former New York Giants linebacker Harry Carson who was diagnosed with post-concussion syndrome and advocated for other players to join a lawsuit against the NFL over brain injuries discusses why he regrets ever playing football.

This journalism is made possible by viewers like you. Donate to FRONTLINE now: https://bit.ly/47DFzCb

And support your local PBS station here: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Harry Carson spoke to FRONTLINE’s Michael Kirk on Sept. 4, 2013, for our 2013 documentary, “League of Denial.” The interview has been edited for accuracy and clarity as part of an editorial and legal review. See a more complete description of our process here: https://to.pbs.org/4lVZKzA

This interview is being published as part of FRONTLINE’s Transparency Project, an effort to open up the source material behind our documentaries. Read more about this project here: https://www.pbs.org/wgbh/frontline/about-frontlines-transparency-project/

“League of Denial” is available to watch here: https://youtu.be/SedClkAnclk

Explore more of our extended interviews in this playlist: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL_pPc6-qR9ZzEepVsKZsT58XiLb38Tttr

 #HarryCarson #Football #BrainInjuries

Subscribe on YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/user/PBSfrontline
Sign up for our newsletter: https://frontline.org/newsletter
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/frontlinepbs
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/frontline
Bluesky: https://bsky.app/profile/frontlinepbs.bsky.social

FRONTLINE is produced at GBH in Boston and airs nationwide on PBS.

The editor-in-chief and executive producer of FRONTLINE is Raney Aronson-Rath.

Funding for FRONTLINE is provided through the support of PBS viewers and by the Corporation for Public Broadcasting, with major support from Ford Foundation. Additional support for FRONTLINE is provided by the Abrams Foundation, Park Foundation, John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, Heising-Simons Foundation, and the FRONTLINE Trust, with major support from Jon and Jo Ann Hagler on behalf of the Jon L. Hagler Foundation, and additional support from Koo and Patricia Yuen.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Illinois Gov. JB Pritzker speaks about his weight loss #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/ruTSZhdAL18</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ruTSZhdAL18?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:59:50 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Does Illinois Gov. JB Pritzker’s recent weight loss point to a potential 2028 presidential run? 👀 He sets the record straight in a conversation with Vox’s Astead Herndon. 

You can watch their full interview on Saturday wherever you get your podcasts or here on YouTube.

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Paul Revere&apos;s Midnight Ride, myth or true? 🐴#AmericanRevolutionPBS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/xUVPmPYb9rs</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/xUVPmPYb9rs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:01:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Historians are in agreement that Paul Revere did alert colonial rebels that soldiers were on the move in April of 1775, but he wasn't alone and his now famous quote: "The British are coming!" is an inaccuracy, it's just not how colonial people would have spoken at the time. The phrase is likely shaped by a popular poem written nearly a century after the events.

Made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS app!

#shorts #myths #historyfacts #history #hero]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Humanity in the midst of war - Survival and loss in Ukraine | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EVW8igV-jhA</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EVW8igV-jhA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:00:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[They evacuate elderly and sick people, set up medical stations and organize escape routes. New structures of protection, security and dignity are emerging in Ukraine, while war shapes everyday life.

All of Ukraine has been at war since Russia’s full-scale attack in February 2022. It is a war whose repercussions are inescapable. And it is giving rise to new structures that every country would be happier to be able to live without. 
One of these is a network of carers who risk their lives to evacuate elderly and sick people from homes that they are often unable to leave on their own. For some, it’s the first journey of their lives, for others, the last. 
A different team, of forensic scientists and military personnel, works to identify the remains of young soldiers. The bodies of the fallen are then transported across Ukraine to their families so that they can be buried in their hometowns. These tasks are all the more difficult, as they must be accomplished amidst the constant threat of bombs and drones. 
As Russia's war of aggression rages against Ukraine, Yuri Rechinsky documents the everyday lives of those who are too weak to flee, or who care for the dead. He captures impressions of displacement, uncertainty, grief and loss, but also shows moments of solidarity, humor and resilience. "Dear Beautiful Beloved" takes a sober look at the survival strategies of people who retain their humanity in the midst of war.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #ukraine 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Meet Jennifer Siebel Newsom</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/qTx3F0KzkI8</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/qTx3F0KzkI8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:23:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[California’s First Partner sits down with Emily Chang to talk about switching political parties, her acting career and the mission driving her now.

Watch The Circuit

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How Nuclear Power Went From Miracle To Nightmare | Compilation</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P4JdQMG0cVY</link><author>Weird History</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/P4JdQMG0cVY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:00:43 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCc-N24Y5OA0gqbjBwe1ttfA">Weird History</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[One the world reached 'the nuclear age', reality got... interesting. Dicey, to say the least, and definitely not like it was before nuclear weapons. Today we are offering a compilation of insightful, scary, and downright interesting videos about all things nuclear. What exactly happened that caused the Chernobyl Meltdown in 1986? How about the American nuclear accident at 3 Mile Island? What plans does the U.S. government have in place in the event of a nuclear attack? What are nuclear bunkers made of? All fo these, and a number of other  wild nuclear situations all in one compilation for you. What part freaks you out the most, or do you find most interesting? Let us know in the comments!


Chapter:
00:00:00 - Everything That Had To Go Wrong For Chernobyl To Happen
00:11:02 - Everything That Went Wrong on 3-Mile Island
00:21:28 - How a Soviet Soldier Saved the World From Annihilation
00:31:57 - Everything The US Government Has Planned For Surviving A Nuclear Attack
00:43:13 - How He Stumbled Upon The US Government's Nuclear Bunkers
00:50:42 - Creepiest Chernobyl Stories You've Never Heard

Be sure to subscribe to the Weird History Newsletter: https://bit.ly/WeirdHistoryNews

#compilation #nuclear #weirdhistory]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Brian Cox Flies to Earth&apos;s &apos;Thin Blue Line&apos; | Wonders Of The Solar System | BBC Earth Science</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=233_krF8KM0</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/233_krF8KM0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:00:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">BBC Earth Science</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Whilst in South Africa, Professor Brian Cox gets aboard the now discontinued  English Electric Lightning Jet and flies around 18 kilometres to reach the atmospheric edge of the Earth to see the 'thin blue line' that protects us down below.

Best of Earth Science: http://bit.ly/EarthLabOriginals 
Best of BBC Earth: http://bit.ly/TheBestOfBBCEarthVideos 

Taken from: Wonders of the Solar System (2010)

This is a channel from BBC Studios who help fund new BBC programmes. Service information and feedback: http://bbcworldwide.com/vod-feedback--contact-details.aspx]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>AI Fails at 96% of Jobs (New Study)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z3kaLM8Oj4o</link><author>ColdFusion</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/z3kaLM8Oj4o?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:56:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC4QZ_LsYcvcq7qOsOhpAX4A">ColdFusion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence has been hailed as one of the most transformative technologies of the century. That may be so, but just not yet. In this episode, we take a look at a study that pits humans directly against AI for paid work. The results were surprising. 
Study here: https://www.remotelabor.ai/paper.pdf
Website: https://www.remotelabor.ai

Watch or listen to ColdFusion on Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/1YEwCKoRz8fEDqheXB6UJ1


ColdFusion Music: 
http://burnwater.bandcamp.com   
https://www.youtube.com/@ColdFusionmusic


ColdFusion Socials: 

https://discord.gg/coldfusion
https://facebook.com/ColdFusionTV 
https://twitter.com/ColdFusion_TV 
https://instagram.com/coldfusiontv

Created by: Dagogo Altraide
Producers: Tawsif Akkas, Dagogo Altraide]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why GLP-1 drugs are a solution for some and a problem for others #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/ncr0U4nEma0</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ncr0U4nEma0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:01:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[GLP-1 drugs seem to be everywhere these days. One in eight adults say they’re taking the drugs. And brands like Wegovy and Ro even ran commercials during the Super Bowl. But are GLP-1s a one-size-fits-all solution? Not exactly. 

Clinical psychologist Dr. Sera Lavelle spoke to Today, Explained guest host Jonquilyn Hill about whether GLP-1 drugs are harmful or hurtful, and why the answer to that question is nuanced and dependent on a patient’s history. 

You can listen to the full episode of Today, Explained wherever you get your podcasts. 

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Is bigger better when it comes to muscles? | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/2rAlkuiC8PI</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/2rAlkuiC8PI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:00:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Muscles can do much more than just set our bodies in motion: regular muscle training has a positive impact on our overall health. This is because muscles work in a similar way to an endocrine organ: when activated, muscles release messenger substances called myokines, which directly influence our central organs such as the brain, liver, heart and intestines. If we lose muscle mass, these organs can become diseased, or metabolic disorders like diabetes can develop. Increased strength and muscle mass have been linked to better mental health, increased focus, improved sleep, and stronger immunity. 

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #fitness 
______

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Clean Architecture with Python • Sam Keen &amp; Max Kirchoff</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w_yq--3wSzw</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/w_yq--3wSzw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:26:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This interview was recorded for the GOTO Book Club.
http://gotopia.tech/bookclub

Check out more here:
https://gotopia.tech/episodes/418

Sam Keen - Founder & Researcher at AlteredCraft & Author of "Clean Architecture with Python"
Max Kirchoff - CTO at Ginko & Multidisciplinary Technologist & Creative

RESOURCES
Sam
https://bsky.app/profile/samkeen.bsky.social
https://x.com/samkeen
https://github.com/samkeen
https://www.linkedin.com/in/samkeen
https://samkeen.dev

Max
https://x.com/ProductNihilist
https://github.com/maxkirchoff
https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxkirchoff
https://maxkirchoff.com

Links
https://www.heyginko.com
https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TestPyramid.html

DESCRIPTION
Max Kirchoff interviews Sam Keen about his book "Clean Architecture with Python". Sam, a software developer with 30 years of experience spanning companies from startups to AWS, shares his approach to applying clean architecture principles with Python while maintaining the language's pragmatic nature.

The conversation explores the balance between architectural rigor and practical development, the critical relationship between architecture and testability, and how clean architecture principles can enhance AI-assisted coding workflows. Sam emphasizes that clean architecture isn't an all-or-nothing approach but a set of principles that developers can adapt to their context, with the core value lying in thoughtful dependency management and clear domain modeling.

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Sam Keen • Clean Architecture with Python • https://amzn.to/4pBT5g0
Fabrizio Romano & Heinrich Kruger • Learn Python Programming • https://amzn.to/4myLBIt
Uncle Bob • Clean Code • https://amzn.to/3soPO6k
Uncle Bob • Clean Architecture • https://amzn.to/3x0gjBQ
Eric Evans • Domain-Driven Design • https://amzn.to/3tnGhwm
Naomi Ceder • The Quick Python Book • https://amzn.to/3zwdDOa
Luciano Ramalho • Fluent Python • https://amzn.to/3oSw2je
David Beazley • Python Distilled (Developer's Library) • https://amzn.to/3QjNBEv
Saleem Siddiqui • Learning Test-Driven Development • https://amzn.to/35OMb3n
Maciej «MJ» Jedrzejewski • Master Software Architecture • https://leanpub.com/master-software-architecture


Bluesky (https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com) 
Twitter (https://twitter.com/GOTOcon) 
Instagram (https://www.instagram.com/goto_con) 
LinkedIn (https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-) 
Facebook (https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences) 

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket: gotopia.tech (https://gotopia.tech) 

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR YOUTUBE CHANNEL (https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1)  - new videos posted daily!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Iran’s Leaders Face a Dangerous Moment</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YCEWDCDIHMI</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/YCEWDCDIHMI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 09:00:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Iran’s leadership is under intense pressure. Its bloody crackdown in the face of widespread popular anger and threats by Donald Trump of another US attack have left it with few options for survival.

00:00 Introduction 
01:46 Economic crisis 
04:31 Corruption & mismanagement 
06:26 Nuclear program   
08:00 Regional influence
08:51 Leadership & opposition
10:18 What’s next 

#iran #trump #economy 
--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Iqunix Magi96 Pro &amp; Magi65 Pro review (Kailh Gold Red)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bbFr_xA1ZZU</link><author>Chyrosran22</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bbFr_xA1ZZU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 06:00:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCD0y51PJfvkZNe3y3FR5riw">Chyrosran22</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Skip to 9:08 for a typing demonstration. 
Get it here: https://iqunix.com/products/iqunix-magi75-96-aluminum-low-profile-mechanical-keyboard
Today I'm taking a (rather cranky) look at Iqunix' Magi96 and -65 Pro keyboards. It's always good to cover one of these from time to time. Hope you enjoy the video! :)

My keyboard reviews: http://bit.ly/1TbOtft
My switch teardowns: http://bit.ly/2C1QGHz
My TOP X videos: http://bit.ly/2FmpZfd
My XL typing demos: https://bit.ly/2OoAW3w
My tutorials and featurettes: https://bit.ly/2OrkLUh
My unboxing videos: https://bit.ly/2TSrr0m

I'm Thomas and I do videos and reviews on mechanical keyboards ranging from the most sickening modern RGB gaming keyboards to vintage hardware relics, or sometimes keycaps or keyswitches ranging from Cherry MX to Alps SKCM to IBM buckling springs and anything in between.

Follow me on Twitter for updates on my keyboard videos! https://twitter.com/chyrosran22

The practice sentence was: "Hello my name is Thomas and I'm typing on an Iqunix Magi96 Pro keyboard right now. It's been a while since I did a low-profile keyboard review; this one is alright actually!"]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What’s Up With Greenland?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lUivkIrfKW4</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/lUivkIrfKW4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 22:10:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://ground.news/startalk to stay fully informed on the latest Space and Science news. Save 40% off through our link for unlimited access to the Vantage plan this month.

What's up with Greenland? Neil deGrasse Tyson breaks down some important points about Greenland from a scientific, historical, and geopolitical lens. 

Timestamps:
00:00 - A Strategic Position
03:28 - Melting Ice
05:50 - The Underground Tunnels
07:04 - Geopolitics of Greenland
 
Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Could These Artifacts Rewrite America&apos;s Pre-Columbus History?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z7xUD9_s1WI</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/z7xUD9_s1WI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 22:00:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In 1924, a discovery in the Arizona desert threatened to rewrite American history. Forensic geologist Scott Wolter investigates the Tucson Lead Artifacts - 32 mysterious objects inscribed with Latin and dated to 800 AD. Were these relics left by a precursor to the Knights Templar, or were they part of an elaborate 20th-century hoax? Through microscopic analysis of mineral growth and "desert cement," Wolter provides hard evidence that challenges the traditional narrative of who reached America first. 

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.
Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://bit.ly/4pyExyn

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Is Gavin Newsom Eyeing the White House?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/l3zpyMdmu1M</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/l3zpyMdmu1M?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 19:00:50 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The California governor and First Partner share what they tells their kids when they ask about a 2028 presidential run. Watch The Circuit with Emily Chang.

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Race to Capture an Erupting Volcano (Part 2) | Spectacular Earth | BBC Earth Science</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oB0B2kWq9mc</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/oB0B2kWq9mc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 19:00:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">BBC Earth Science</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Duncan and his expert team get to the final part of their mission as they wait for Guatemala's Volcán de Fuego to erupt - all while trying to get a precision drone to capture the footage.

Best of Earth Science: http://bit.ly/EarthLabOriginals 
Best of BBC Earth: http://bit.ly/TheBestOfBBCEarthVideos 

Taken from: Spectacular Earth (2022)

This is a channel from BBC Studios who help fund new BBC programmes. Service information and feedback: http://bbcworldwide.com/vod-feedback--contact-details.aspx]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>WW2 Historian Explains Bloody Final Days of the War in Europe</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pun2Xy0W-Hc</link><author>History Hit</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/pun2Xy0W-Hc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ">History Hit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Just how brutal was the Soviet Advance on Berlin?

Dan Snow and military historian Sir Antony Beevor present the gripping account of the Battle of Berlin, the final, bloody chapter of World War Two in Europe. The pair discuss Joseph Stalin's secret plan to seize the city and its nuclear secrets while deceiving his Western Allies.

00:00:00 intro
00:01:34 Spring 1945
00:02:51 Target Berlin
00:03:40 Stalin’s Ambitions 
00:04:14 Soviet Advance 
00:05:31 Soviet Forces Breakdown 
00:06:42 Hitler’s Determination & State of German Forces 
00:07:55 April 1945 Soviet Advance on Germany 
00:10:15 American and British Advance 
00:14:00 Distrust Amongst Allies 
00:15:18 The Battle for the Seelow Heights 
00:18:30 Stalin's Plan, Encirclement of Berlin 
00:18:54 State of Adolf Hitler
00:20:30 Hitler’s Inner Circle 
00:22:05 Dying Moments of the Nazi Party 
00:22:50 SS Orgy 
00:24:18 Soviets March on Berlin & German Defence 
00:25:24 Hitler’s Final Day
00:26:00 German Civilians & Hitler’s Nero Order 
00:27:50 Soviets in Berlin, Street Fighting 
00:30:30 French SS & Capture of Reichstag
00:33:00 Soviet Violence in Berlin 
00:35:00 Hitler’s Suicide & Surrender 
00:36:50 Soviet Casualties 
00:38:00 Importance of Berlin 

From the colossal artillery battle at the Seelow Heights to the brutal street fighting in the city, this is the definitive story of the Third Reich's collapse.

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world-renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.

Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ/join

#worldwartwo #battleofberlin #1945]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Illinois Gov. JB Pritzker encourages people to protest ICE #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/WPHK9KZLBfw</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/WPHK9KZLBfw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:01:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[“They’re shooting moms in the face.” 

Illinois Gov. JB Pritzker told Vox’s Astead Herndon that peaceful protesting is the “least” people can do as ICE maintains a presence in Chicago. 
You can watch their full interview on Saturday, here on YouTube.

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Liberland: Crypto paradise or libertarian illusion? | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z5yln5Z5azs</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/z5yln5Z5azs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:01:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Liberland is a country that doesn’t officially exist. A country that promises voluntary taxes and a lean state. It’s a libertarian utopia that’s finding more supporters worldwide.

After the Yugoslav Wars, the border between Serbia and Croatia along the Danube river remained unresolved. Vit Jedlička, a former politician from the Czech Republic, took advantage of this situation. He proclaimed the "Free Republic of Liberland” on a seven-square-kilometer piece of land in 2015. 
Liberland is not internationally recognized, and its president is not allowed to set foot on the soil of his republic. Croatia sees the founding of Liberland as an attack on its territorial integrity.
The film accompanies Samuela Davidova, influencer, crypto enthusiast, and spokesperson for Liberland, and Liberland‘s president, Vit Jedlička, on a journey into two very different worlds. 
On the one hand, they travel to Dubai, a glittering metropolitan meeting place for crypto-enthusiastic elites. Here, they want to recruit investors — and new citizens. 
And on the other hand, they travel to "Ark Village,” the base camp of the Liberland community on Serbian soil. Here, they celebrate the 10th anniversary of Liberland.
The highlight of the journey is a boat trip to the shores of Liberland. Liberland claims to function as a meritocracy: taxes are voluntary, but those who invest more have a greater say. 
The Liberland experiment may seem like an oddity, but it also raises serious questions: Cryptocurrencies and decentralized networks are undermining traditional national borders, and radical market ideas are gaining influence. Parallel structures are emerging. Critics see them as a threat to democracy. Others, of course, sense opportunity. 

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #liberland #crypto #cryptocurrency 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>James Brown’s “Please Please Please” 🎙️ #musichistory</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/WNrQ2_JqwSk</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/WNrQ2_JqwSk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:01:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Witness James Brown bring gospel fire to the secular stage, transforming a simple "Please Please Please" into a moment of pure ecstasy. Feel the raw power of his performance 🎤 Learn more about James Brown's early years in "King of Them All: The Story of King Records", now streaming on the PBS app!

 #JamesBrown #KingofThemAll #Gospel #LivePerformance  

Made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS app!

King of Them All: The Story of King Records
From James Brown’s soul to the Stanley Brothers’ bluegrass, Cincinnati's King Records shaped genres that still echo today. Guided by voices like Seymour Stein, Vince Gill, and Christian McBride, the film restores a lost legacy.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Responsibility of Producing Media</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/X2Pn8rM7MRU</link><author>Horses</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/X2Pn8rM7MRU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrx2zrPjhGRi9TwszZiLwEg">Horses</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Find more at: ⁠https://horses.land]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>3 things that can cause painful periods - Chen X. Chen</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NOaeKRft-gc</link><author>TED-Ed</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/NOaeKRft-gc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsooa4yRKGN_zEE8iknghZA">TED-Ed</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dig into the science of what makes period cramps so painful, and find out what we still don’t know about this common experience.

--

Period pain affects hundreds of millions of people. Anywhere from 50 to 90% of people who menstruate deal with painful abdominal or pelvic cramps during their period. Individual experiences can vary, from mild discomfort, to throbbing aches, to contraction-like cramps that rival the pain of labor. So, why do menstrual cramps hurt so much? Chen X. Chen explains this surprisingly common experience.

Lesson by Chen X. Chen, directed by Caitlin McCarthy.

Support Our Non-Profit Mission
----------------------------------------------
Support us on Patreon: http://bit.ly/TEDEdPatreon
Check out our merch: http://bit.ly/TEDEDShop
----------------------------------------------

Connect With Us
----------------------------------------------
Sign up for our newsletter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdNewsletter
Follow us on Facebook: http://bit.ly/TEDEdFacebook
Find us on Twitter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdTwitter
Peep us on Instagram: http://bit.ly/TEDEdInstagram
----------------------------------------------

Keep Learning
----------------------------------------------
View full lesson: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/3-things-that-cause-painful-periods-chen-x-chen
Dig deeper with additional resources: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/3-things-that-cause-painful-periods-chen-x-chen/digdeeper

Animator's website: https://www.strangebeast.tv/directors/caitlin-mccarthy
Music: https://www.workplaywork.com
----------------------------------------------

Thank you so much to our patrons for your support! Without you this video would not be possible! Jay M, Constantino Victor Delgado, Andrea Galvagni, Andrew Tweddle, Laurel-Ann Rice, Fernando A. Endo, Helen Lee, pam morgan, sarim haq, Gerardo Castro, Michel-Ange Hortegat, Enes Kirimi, Amaury BISIAUX, ND, Samyogita Hardikar, Vanessa Graulich, Vandana Gunwani, Abdulmohsin Almadi, AJ Lyon, Geoffrey Bultitude, Mi Mi, Thomas Rothert, Brian Elieson, Oge O, Weronika Falkowska, Nevin Spoljaric, Sid Chanpuriya, Anoop Varghese, David Yastremski, Noah Webb, Roberto Chena, Oliver Koo, Luke Pisano, Andrea Gordon, Aleksandar Donev, Nicole Klau Ibarra, Jesse Lira, Ezekiel Raui, Petr Vacek, Dennis, Olivia Fu, Kari Teffeau, Cindy Lai, Rajath Durgada Manjunath, Dan Nguyen, Chin Beng Tan, Tom Boman, Karen Warner, Iryna Panasiuk, and Aaron Torres.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Rubber used to be useless…</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/Bl0WZvAeDik</link><author>Veritasium</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Bl0WZvAeDik?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:02:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA">Veritasium</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Watch the full video here: https://youtu.be/AFXLZ7FEJc4?si=OaiAz42CzKGSPOYh

Written by Sulli Yost and @casper_mebius

Produced and Directed by Sulli Yost

Hosted by Derek Muller and @henry.vandyck

#science  #veritasium  #physics  #engineering  #experiment]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Inside Malaysia’s Controversial Anti-Corruption Commission</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/bxjhskwx9YE</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bxjhskwx9YE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:37:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Malaysian Anti-Corruption Commission was set up to fight graft. Now some of its members have been accused of the very wrongdoing they are meant to stop, allegedly helping a group of businessmen seize control of companies. 

Questions about the commission’s conduct go all the way to the top.  

Watch the full story

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>After Q-Day: Quantum Applications at Scale • Matthew Keesan • YOW! 2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oE9dGufCxoo</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/oE9dGufCxoo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:01:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This presentation was recorded at YOW! Australia 2025. #GOTOcon #YOW
https://yowcon.com

Matthew Keesan - VP & GM at IonQ

RESOURCES
https://twitter.com/keesan
https://github.com/mjk
https://www.linkedin.com/in/keesan
https://www.keesan.net

Links
https://plus.maths.org/content/hypersphere-in-4D
https://iontrap.duke.edu/2021/10/19/fault-tolerant-operation-of-a-quantum-error-correction-code
https://www.csiro.au/en/news/All/News/2025/October/Breakthrough-quantum-secure-link-protects-data-using-the-laws-of-physics
https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.08732
https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.22408
https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.13128
https://www.scottaaronson.com/democritus
https://github.com/Munich-Quantum-Software-Stack
https://openqse.org
https://unitary.foundation

ABSTRACT
In the span of one generation, quantum computers have gone from thought experiments to globally deployed commercial products on the verge of becoming a standard tool in high-performance computing (HPC).

Much early motivation in (and funding for) developing practical quantum computers resulted from Peter Shor's discovery of an efficient quantum algorithm for factorization—thereby threatening the RSA encryption standard. If today's quantum computing manufacturers achieve their roadmaps, RSA-2048 will be broken within the next few years. Beyond a sea change for encrypted communications globally, this heralds the arrival of a new era of HPC workflows and the possibility of solving heretofore unsolvable problems.

In this talk, we will discuss the current state of research into what applications might come online first, the nascent ecosystems for delivering them, and the call to action to all developers to prepare for Q-Day and beyond! [...]

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
00:56 What is Q-Day?
01:18 What is quantum computing?
09:05 How to start worrying about Q-day
20:01 Complexity theory in 100 seconds
20:48 BQP: Bounded-error quantum polynomial time
27:53 Part 1: Quantum AI
30:16 Part 2: Quantum chemistry & materials science
33:20 Part 3: Modeling & simulation
34:05 Part 4: You?
37:45 Outro

Read the full abstract here:
https://yowcon.com/brisbane-2025/sessions/3916

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Scott Aaronson • Quantum Computing Since Democritus • https://amzn.to/3kSH0nG
Johan Vos • Quantum Computing in Action (available soon) • https://amzn.to/3oj7OQ6
Jack D. Hidary • Quantum Computing: An Applied Approach • https://amzn.to/3kdJ3CK
Sarah C. Kaiser & Christopher Grenade • Learn Quantum Computing with Python and Q# • https://amzn.to/3CgL6f8
Venkateswaran Kasirajan • Fundamentals of Quantum Computing • https://amzn.to/3nzk7aL
Brian Clegg • Quantum Computing: The Transformative Technology of the Qubit Revolution • https://amzn.to/3AcdmiI
William (Chuck) Easttom • Quantum Computing Fundamentals • https://amzn.to/2ZzUUTy
Wolfgang Scherer • Mathematics of Quantum Computing • https://amzn.to/3CXYBRl

https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com
https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#Quantum #QuantumComputing #QuantumComputer #QDay #QuantumAI #QC #Programming #Qubits #Qubit #QuantumAnnealing #QPU #HPC #BQP #BoundedErrorQuantumPolynomialTime #HighPerformanceComputing #DowlingNeven #Superconducting #ComplexityTheory #SoftwareEngineering #MatthewKeesan #YOWcon

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mustang vs Thunderbolt - Pros and Cons</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/Mnk50KYRKN4</link><author>Imperial War Museums</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Mnk50KYRKN4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3uAjWoLZ4bSi6qI9SjALxA">Imperial War Museums</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#history #p51 #mustang #aviation #ww2planes]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Exhibiting WWII Arms (RA Winter Lecture)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=54QKuEyxFLM</link><author>Royal Armouries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/54QKuEyxFLM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 03:15:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsMX-XuiEkBi4-GDrYuniWg">Royal Armouries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[How to exhibit arms: Weapons and technologies of the two World Wars in contemporary museums.

Speaker: Dr Stephan Jaeger, Professor of German Studies, University of Manitoba

Discover how the weapons of the two World Wars have been exhibited in contemporary museums in Europe and North America, highlighting military success and innovation, but also dehumanization and destruction.

Subscribe to our channel for more videos about arms and armour  

Help us bring history to life by supporting us here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/donations/

Sign up to our museum membership scheme here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/membership/ 

⚔Website: https://royalarmouries.org/home
⚔Blog: https://royalarmouries.org/stories/
⚔Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/RoyalArmouriesMuseum/
⚔Twitter: https://twitter.com/Royal_Armouries
⚔ Instagram: http://instagram.com/royalarmouriesmuseum

We are the Royal Armouries, the United Kingdom's national collection of arms and armour. Discover what goes on behind the scenes and watch our collection come to life. See combat demonstrations, experience jousting and meet our experts. 

Have a question about arms and armour? Feel free to leave us a comment and we'll do our best to answer it.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Inside The B-29 Superfortress: The Deadliest Bomber In History</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n-Ko-gmxaPE</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/n-Ko-gmxaPE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:00:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Discover the untold story of the United States Army Air Forces and their pivotal role in WW2. Using newly restored archival footage, we trace the journey from the desperate early days of the Pacific to the massive "carpet bombing" campaigns in Normandy. Witness the engineering marvel of the B-29 Superfortress, the grueling construction of airfields in China, and the strategic air battles that dismantled the Luftwaffe and the Japanese Empire. This is the definitive record of the men and machines that secured Allied air supremacy.

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.
Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://bit.ly/4pyExyn

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Inside Malaysia’s Controversial Anti-Corruption Commission | Bloomberg Investigates</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pQ83FaJlGHo</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/pQ83FaJlGHo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:00:54 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Malaysian Anti-Corruption Commission was set up to fight graft. Now some of its members have been accused of the very wrongdoing they are meant to stop, allegedly helping a group of businessmen seize control of companies. Questions about the commission’s conduct go all the way to the top.  

Who’s Watching Malaysia’s Anti-Corruption Watchdog?
https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2026-02-11/malaysia-macc-allegedly-working-with-businessmen-to-seize-control-of-companies

Bloomberg Investigates is an award-winning series that sets out to uncover the truth behind some of the most powerful stories from around the world. Watch more: https://www.youtube.com/show/VLPLqq4LnWs3olVK53n-XDSRF10i6THmbCEx?sbp=QAE%3D

#Malaysia #Corruption #Documentary

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>