<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Youtube</title><link>https://konrad.website/liveboat-github-runner/</link><description></description><item><title>Leeches Are A Walking Blood Bank | Save Our Species | BBC Earth</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ED2OEBQ7y6g</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ED2OEBQ7y6g?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 17:05:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">BBC Earth Science</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[It can be difficult for conservationists to accurately survey the animals that live in a certain area. Thankfully they have an unlikely ally – the leech. By analysing the blood they have consumed, they can get an accurate picture of the wildlife in a local area.

#WildlifeConservation #Nature #Wildlife 

Best of Earth Science: http://bit.ly/EarthLabOriginals 
Best of BBC Earth: http://bit.ly/TheBestOfBBCEarthVideos 

This is a channel from BBC Studios who help fund new BBC programmes. Service information and feedback: http://bbcworldwide.com/vod-feedback--contact-details.aspx]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How Germany&apos;s elite research institution fails young scientists | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n5nEd600iM0</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/n5nEd600iM0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 17:00:57 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Max Planck Society is a figurehead of scientific research in Germany: a big name, a stellar reputation, and top-notch facilities. Anyone who makes it to one of its 84 institutes belongs to the elite: an organization that counts 31 Nobel Prize laureates among its ranks. But there is a dark side to its facade.
 
For months, DW's investigative unit, along with German news magazine Der Spiegel, has investigated allegations of misconduct perpetrated by senior scientific staff at Max Planck institutes. We spoke to more than 30 young scientists, many who described abusive behavior and toxic environments. They were afraid to report the abuse, fearing the consequences, and the few who did report say they were discouraged from doing so.
 
DW goes behind the scenes of Germany's elite research institutes to find out why abusive behavior and toxic work environments remain resilient in the face of opposition.
 
If you have a tip, feel free to contact DW's investigative unit here: https://www.dw.com/en/do-you-have-confidential-information-that-you-want-to-share-with-dw/a-61899300

#documentary #investigation #reporter #dwstories #dwdocumentary 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/dwdochindi
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Smith &amp; Wesson Model 10-11 with firearms expert Jonathan Ferguson</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m1rK1ObR0uQ</link><author>Royal Armouries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/m1rK1ObR0uQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 16:23:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsMX-XuiEkBi4-GDrYuniWg">Royal Armouries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Today's episode revolves around a Revolver with some historical significance and represents the 'last gasp' of revolvers within UK Police service. 

0:00 Intro
0:14 S&W Model 10-11 Revolver
0:54 Police Use
1:23 Lockerbie Trial
2:30 Police Firearms
3:35 A Holy Trigger
4:38 Service History 
6:10 Armoury Tag
7:09 Predecessor
8:00 Rounds
8:10 Further Reading...
9:00 Outro

Sources:
 
Frederick Wilkinson. ‘Those Entrusted With Arms’ (Greenhill Books, 2002).
 
https://www.scotcourts.gov.uk/judgments/lockerbie-trial/

https://www.shutterstock.com/editorial/image-editorial/kamp-zeist-soesterberg-nederland-lockerbie-trail-320493d

https://www.gettyimages.co.uk/detail/news-photo/scottish-policeman-armed-with-an-automatic-weapon-stands-news-photo/1245578285

Comical 1980s Footage of Met Police Officers in Weapons Training (1987) by ITN Archives [Available here: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GKvLx6n2Itw ] 

Subscribe to our channel for more videos about arms and armour  

Help us bring history to life by supporting us here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/donations/

Sign up to our museum membership scheme here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/membership/ 

⚔Website: https://royalarmouries.org/home
⚔Blog: https://royalarmouries.org/stories/
⚔Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/RoyalArmouriesMuseum/
⚔Twitter: https://twitter.com/Royal_Armouries
⚔ Instagram: http://instagram.com/royalarmouriesmuseum

We are the Royal Armouries, the United Kingdom's national collection of arms and armour. Discover what goes on behind the scenes and watch our collection come to life. See combat demonstrations, experience jousting and meet our experts. 

Have a question about arms and armour? Feel free to leave us a comment and we'll do our best to answer it.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Tim Walz, live at SXSW with Today, Explained</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=47GYyXVTUFY</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/47GYyXVTUFY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 16:00:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz sat down with Today, Explained Host Sean Rameswaram at SXSW in Austin, Texas, to talk about 2024, 2025, and what might help his party in 2028.

This episode was recorded live on the Vox Media Podcast Stage at SXSW, presented by Smartsheet.

Support our work. Become a Vox Member today: http://www.vox.com/memberships

Today, Explained is Vox’s daily news explainer podcast. Hosts Sean Rameswaram and Noel King will guide you through the most important stories of the day. You can listen to it, and more Vox podcasts, here. Today, Explained is now available on public radio stations across the US.

You can find all their episodes here: https://www.vox.com/today-explained-podcast 

And their Tim Walz SXSW episode here:  https://open.spotify.com/episode/6jRvadX7T2oJ9DZcrcysJs?si=99a0ae586e2f4fe8 

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Electromagnetic Railguns (RA Winter Lecture)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v3FdIa6PMyg</link><author>Royal Armouries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/v3FdIa6PMyg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 15:20:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsMX-XuiEkBi4-GDrYuniWg">Royal Armouries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In this lecture, former research engineer Derek Putley will review UK experimental work from the 1980s and 1990s, including the origin story of a wooden railgun model now held at the Royal Armouries.

‘Enough of this. Bring up the railguns, let’s finish this and go home.’ - MCRN Captain Theresa Yao, The Expanse, 2015

Electromagnetic railguns are guns powered by electricity instead of chemical propellants. Most will be familiar with railguns as futuristic weapons featured in science fiction. To date, many countries have carried out experimental and theoretical studies of railguns but none has yet developed them into practical weapons.

The lecture will explore the scientific principles of railgun operation and some of the engineering challenges involved. Derek will also explore some of his experiences from UK experimental work from the 1980s and 1990s, when railguns were seen as potential future anti-tank weapons.

This will include the design and patenting of a railswitch breech for the RARDE experimental programme. He will shed light on the full size wooden model of the patented railswitch breech, now held in the Royal Armouries collection at Fort Nelson (object number XIX.852). He will also talk about his work on the Hyperlocity Test Facility railgun at Culham Laboratory.

Subscribe to our channel for more videos about arms and armour  

Help us bring history to life by supporting us here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/donations/

Sign up to our museum membership scheme here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/membership/ 

⚔Website: https://royalarmouries.org/home
⚔Blog: https://royalarmouries.org/stories/
⚔Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/RoyalArmouriesMuseum/
⚔Twitter: https://twitter.com/Royal_Armouries
⚔ Instagram: http://instagram.com/royalarmouriesmuseum

We are the Royal Armouries, the United Kingdom's national collection of arms and armour. Discover what goes on behind the scenes and watch our collection come to life. See combat demonstrations, experience jousting and meet our experts. 

Have a question about arms and armour? Feel free to leave us a comment and we'll do our best to answer it.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Operation Desert Storm | Hour-by-Hour</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ty5SDNSIjnc</link><author>Imperial War Museums</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ty5SDNSIjnc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 14:32:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3uAjWoLZ4bSi6qI9SjALxA">Imperial War Museums</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[On the 26th of February 1991, Captain Tim Purbrick noticed Iraqi tanks in the distance. One of them, a T-55, was 4,700 metres or nearly 3 miles away, four times the battle range of his Challenger 1. When his crew fired the main gun, the round took nearly three full seconds to reach the target. When it did, a massive fireball erupted in the distance. Purbrick’s crew had just achieved the longest tank-to-tank kill in military history. That T-55 was one of many Iraqi tanks which never even saw the enemy coming.

In this third episode of our Gulf War Series IWM Curator Megan Joyce uncovers the challenges faced by Coalition forces, the mass deception tactics employed, and the pivotal role of GPS in navigating the Iraqi desert. Join us as we examine the intense battles, including the Battle of 73 Easting and the Battle of Norfolk, and the final withdrawal of Iraqi troops.

Find out more about the Gulf War: https://www.iwm.org.uk/history/what-was-the-gulf-war

See our objects for yourself. Plan your visit to IWM Duxford: 
https://www.iwm.org.uk/visits/iwm-duxford

Explore and licence the film clips used in this video from IWM Film: 
https://film.iwmcollections.org.uk/collections/_DEbW5lOw

Follow IWM on social media:
https://twitter.com/I_W_M
https://www.instagram.com/imperialwarmuseums
https://www.facebook.com/iwm.london

#war  #history  #desertstorm]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>This is how astronomers found the furthest star we have ever seen! #ThinkAgain #Shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W9zSiQYnJH8</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/W9zSiQYnJH8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 14:30:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">BBC Earth Science</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Best of Earth Science: http://bit.ly/EarthLabOriginals 
Best of BBC Earth: http://bit.ly/TheBestOfBBCEarthVideos 

This is a channel from BBC Studios who help fund new BBC programmes. Service information and feedback: http://bbcworldwide.com/vod-feedback--contact-details.aspx]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Bloomberg Primer Trailer | Premieres March 20</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fz8o1cN7mWA</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Fz8o1cN7mWA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 14:13:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Bloomberg Primer cuts through the complex jargon to reveal the business behind technologies poised to transform global markets. Watch our planet-spanning series for a comprehensive look at the "impossible" industries vying to shape our future. 

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for $1.99/month for the first 3 months: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals

Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg Quicktake for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What&apos;s up with Rust? • Tim McNamara • GOTO 2024</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pppU--kHLP0</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/pppU--kHLP0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 13:01:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This presentation was recorded at GOTO Copenhagen 2024. #GOTOcon #GOTOcph
https://gotocph.com

Tim McNamara - Author of "Rust in Action", Software Consultant & Coach @timClicks 

RESOURCES
https://bsky.app/profile/timclicks.dev
https://timclicks.dev
https://mastodon.nz/@timClicks
https://github.com/timclicks
https://twitter.com/timClicks
https://linkedin.com/in/timmcnamaranz
https://www.rustinaction.com
https://doc.rust-lang.org/stable/book

Links
https://msrc.microsoft.com/blog/2019/07/we-need-a-safer-systems-programming-language
https://security.googleblog.com/2022/12/memory-safe-languages-in-android-13.html

ABSTRACT
An informative guide to what is special about the Rust programming language and how to bring the best parts of it into your software project, whichever programming language it's implemented in.

Rust programmers spend a lot of time thinking about lifetimes, ownership and borrowing. So should you! These concepts are actually universal in programming. Rust's approach is to encode them into the type system and make the compiler check that you're obeying the rules (that you manually check anyway).

We'll also learn about some of its language features, including algebraic data types, error handling, and how it can guarantee that (the equivalent of) a NullPointerExeception will never occur. This language that brings memory safety to systems programming has much to share. Come and learn! [...]

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
00:52 2022 was so long ago
03:50 By 2024, things started to change
06:14 A tiny bit of Rust
09:32 Central concepts
10:16 Ownership
11:26 Lifetimes
12:18 Borrowing
15:02 Demo
20:01 Error handling
20:20 Demo
31:45 Why is Rust so fast?
32:22 No garbage collector
34:44 Stack heavy
37:15 Minimal overhead for high-level constructs
39:13 Outro

Download slides and read the full abstract here:
https://gotocph.com/2024/sessions/3315

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Tim McNamara • Rust in Action • https://amzn.to/3ux2R9u
Brenden Matthews • Code Like a Pro in Rust • https://amzn.to/3LFAyy9
Prabhu Eshwarla • Rust Servers, Services & Apps • https://amzn.to/3yV13br
Bastian Gruber • Rust Web Development • https://amzn.to/3lquaQX
Blandy, Orendorff & Tindall • Programming Rust • https://amzn.to/3x7r6w6
Ken Youens-Clark • Command-Line Rust • https://amzn.to/3PQZ539
Kevin Hoffman • Programming WebAssembly with Rust • https://amzn.to/3x3brhe
Richard Feldman • Elm in Action • https://amzn.to/387kujI

https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com
https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#Rustlang #RustInAction #Rust #MemorySafety #SystemsProgramming #ComputerScience #TimMcNamara #SoftwareEngineering #Programming #PersistentStorage #Networking #SegmentationFault #FunctionalProgramming

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Did Donald Trump Dump 2 Billion Gallons of Water Into A Hole?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E0VodzjxPDE</link><author>Sarcasmitron</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/E0VodzjxPDE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 19:15:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC6WD1VImCVeOuNccuqDzAdA">Sarcasmitron</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://ground.news/sarcasmitron
 to unlock tools for comparing news coverage on this election, and to stay informed on world news. Subscribe through my link for 40% off unlimited access.

For more information about Trump and California's fight over water, watch my first video on this topic:
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aux22FHTFXQ

Sources:
https://calmatters.org/environment/water/2024/12/california-delta-water-delivery-rules/
https://calmatters.org/environment/2023/02/newsom-environmental-laws-store-more-delta-water/
https://calmatters.org/environment/water/2024/10/california-delta-plan-trump-newsom-salmon/
https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environment/2025/03/07/trump-water-release-california-fires/


Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/user?u=2646842
Twitter:   https://www.x.com/afran90
BlueSky: https://bsky.app/profile/sarcasmitron...
Ko-Fi: https://ko-fi.com/sarcasmitron]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Arrested by my Ex Boyfriend</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5_9voK0QVvY</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/5_9voK0QVvY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 18:40:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Are Dyson Spheres even plausible? ☀️</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wrbeXNYfRS8</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wrbeXNYfRS8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 18:01:43 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Be sure to follow: The Astronomical Society @astrosocietypac 

Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Answering Questions about Hubble Tension, Dyson Spheres, &amp; Relativity</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y8b93R3kfso</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/y8b93R3kfso?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 18:01:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Is “now” just an illusion? Neil deGrasse Tyson and comic co-host Paul Mecurio answer questions on the Higgs Field, dark energy, and the feasibility of Dyson spheres with astrophysicist Hakeem Oluseyi.

We discuss Hakeem’s role as CEO of the Astronomical Society, and his work on NASA’s IMAP satellite, designed to study the boundary of our solar system. He shares his vision for making astronomy more accessible, the difference between nerds and geeks, and why he doesn’t wear gold.

Then, we tackle the growing mystery of the universe’s expansion. Is the Hubble tension a sign of undiscovered physics? Could our cosmological models need tweaking? We explore the role of dark energy, the Higgs field, and the unanswered questions that keep physicists awake at night.

Next, we turn our sights to exoplanets. How do scientists detect distant atmospheres? What can JWST reveal? And when it comes to dark matter—could it be defying our understanding of physics itself? We break down theories, alternative gravity models, and the possibility that new technology may finally uncover what’s been eluding us.

Plus, we tackle gravitational waves and time itself—what would happen if we were hit by one? Is “now” just an illusion? We break down the Andromeda Paradox and also touch on black holes, information loss, and the search for Dyson spheres. Could an advanced civilization really build one, or is it just sci-fi fantasy? All this, plus a look at the biggest roadblock in STEM education, the history of mathematical knowledge, and how we can get more people looking up. 

Timestamps:
00:00 - Introduction: Hakeem Oluseyi
03:30 - The Astronomical Society @astrosocietypac 
9:31 - IMAP
14:32 - How Do We Resolve Hubble Tension?
25:25 - Detecting Atmospheres of Distant Planets
27:29 - Better Tools or Better Physics to Unlock Dark Matter
32:41 - Can Gravitational Waves Alter Time? 
37:30 - What is the Conservation of Information?
41:01 - The Big Squeeze
41:36 - Get Those Dyson Spheres Out of Your Head
44:38 - Closing Thoughts

Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dublin&apos;s housing shortage - Families despair at rising rents | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZOTgP2D_qmQ</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ZOTgP2D_qmQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:00:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Ireland is facing a short-fall of hundreds of thousands of homes, especially in Dublin. As rents rise, so does homelessness. With no house or apartment, Jordyn, Jonathan and their young daughter Delilah have to find a new place to sleep every night.

The young family has been searching for permanent accommodation in Ireland's capital for ten months. Their everyday life involves appointments with the local authorities and endless hours spent on hold on the telephone. They are unable to afford Dublin’s high rents, and social housing seems beyond their reach. Each day, Jordyn, Jonathan and their daughter try to arrange to stay the night with friends or relatives.

Justin is a social worker. He previously worked with homeless people in a privately run emergency shelter. But when the shelter was sold, he lost his job and his home. Now, he spends his days combing through offers on the overpriced housing market. But the few available homes are usually either unaffordable or unsuitable. Single rooms, and even individual beds, are being rented out at fantastical prices.

Conor is currently completing his doctoral thesis, and lives with his girlfriend in a tiny apartment. The housing shortage has turned him into a political activist: he’s running for a seat on the city council and helping to raise awareness of the problem. He collects signatures for a petition to stop apartments being left empty, and for more affordable housing.

Despite the government’s promises, Ireland remains in the midst of a seemingly never-ending housing crisis. For Jordyn, Jonathan and little Delilah, there’s light at the end of the tunnel. But for many others, the situation remains desperate. 

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #ireland  #housing 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/dwdochindi
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Covid-19 pandemic: When the world stood still | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QkYaMcaT-zg</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/QkYaMcaT-zg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:23:50 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Five years ago, on March 11, 2020, Covid-19 was officially declared a pandemic. The deadly disease spread so quickly around the world that it could not be stopped with known measures.  

For many people, like César Serrano, it was as if time had stopped, “it's as if a huge storm has come and wiped out everything. Everything is completely deserted, lifeless, closed.” 

It felt like something out of a disaster movie. First came the fear of this unknown virus, followed by lockdowns. Once the first wave had passed, restrictions in some places were eased. Then came further waves and restrictions, but people got used to the changes in their daily life.  

As the pandemic entered its second year, expressions of solidarity, seen at the start, gave way to frustration and anger. People took to the streets in anti-government protests and conspiracy theories spread. People also began to question the price they had paid for efforts made at protecting themselves and others against this virus. 

What impact did the coronavirus pandemic have on our life?

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs
______

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The century-old technology that could change the world - Rachel Yang</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f-T0PEWRaVc</link><author>TED-Ed</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/f-T0PEWRaVc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 15:01:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsooa4yRKGN_zEE8iknghZA">TED-Ed</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dig into the science of thermal batteries, and how this technology can generate heat more efficiently than fossil fuels.

--

Industrial manufacturers spend a huge amount of energy generating heat to make everyday materials and objects, like cement, steel, and paper. And since most companies use fossil fuels to reach these high temperatures, industrial heat accounts for 20% of our annual global carbon pollution. Thankfully, this is where a century-old technology comes in. Rachel Yang explores how heat batteries work.

Lesson by Rachel Yang, directed by Sofia Pashaei.

This video made possible in collaboration with Speed & Scale
Learn more about how TED-Ed partnerships work: https://bit.ly/TEDEdPartner

Support Our Non-Profit Mission
----------------------------------------------
Support us on Patreon: http://bit.ly/TEDEdPatreon
Check out our merch: http://bit.ly/TEDEDShop
----------------------------------------------

Connect With Us
----------------------------------------------
Sign up for our newsletter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdNewsletter
Follow us on Facebook: http://bit.ly/TEDEdFacebook
Find us on Twitter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdTwitter
Peep us on Instagram: http://bit.ly/TEDEdInstagram
----------------------------------------------

Keep Learning
----------------------------------------------
View full lesson: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/how-giant-toasters-could-power-the-world-rachel-yang
Dig deeper with additional resources: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/how-giant-toasters-could-power-the-world-rachel-yang/digdeeper
----------------------------------------------

Thank you so much to our patrons for your support! Without you this video would not be possible! OnlineBookClub.org, Eric Shear, Leith Salem, Omar Hicham, Adrian Rotaru, Brad Sullivan, Karen Ho, Niklas Frimberger, Hunter Manhart, Nathan Nguyen, Igor Stavchanskiy, James R DeVries, Grace Huo, Diana Huang, Chau Hong Diem, Orlellys Torre, Corheu, Thomas Mee, Maryann H McCrory, Blas Borde, John Hellmann, Poompak Meephian, Chuck Wofford, Adam Pagan, Wes Winn, Conder Shou, ntiger, Noname, Hansan Hu, David D, Mac Hyney, Keith Ellison, robin valero walters, Lynne Truesdale, Gatsby Dkdc, Matthew Neal, Denis Chon, Julian Oberhofer, Monte Carroll, Eddy, Jay M, Constantino Victor Delgado, Andrea Galvagni, Andrew Tweddle, Laurel-Ann Rice, Fernando A. Endo, Helen Lee, pam morgan, sarim haq, and Gerardo Castro.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Fight to Preserve and Revitalize the CHamoru Language in Guam | PBS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Sknr3GqIKA8</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Sknr3GqIKA8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 15:00:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Follow filmmaker Brian Muna as he seeks to reconnect with CHamoru, the language native to the people of Guam and elders in his family. In his search for identity, he examines his culturally American upbringing and the importance of passing on the CHamoru language and traditions to his sons. As he meets with language advocates and youth in Guam, he wonders, is there hope for future generations of CHamoru speakers to preserve the language?

'HOMEGROWN: A Part Of/Apart From' is a collection of short films from the U.S. territories and Hawaiʻi exploring issues of cultural identity, sovereignty, and agency, as residents and members of the diaspora grapple with what it means to be “a part of and apart from” the mainland U.S.

CHamoru: A Lost Language | HOMEGROWN

This program is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Subscribe to the PBS channel for more clips:  https://www.youtube.com/PBS/

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS App: https://to.pbs.org/2QbtzhR

FOLLOW US:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/PBS/
X: https://twitter.com/PBS/
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/PBS/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@pbs
Threads: https://www.threads.net/@pbs

#guam #chamorro #language #languagelearning]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Graveyard at the Center of the Earth</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=din1J2mZmc4</link><author>PBS Eons</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/din1J2mZmc4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzR-rom72PHN9Zg7RML9EbA">PBS Eons</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[It's Patron Appreciation Month at Eons, and you're invited! To celebrate, join us for a livestream on March 27. Become a member at https://www.patreon.com/eons at the Paleozoic level or above by March 31 and receive the very first Eons trading card! Plus, show your love for Eons and the Permian Era with our new t-shirt: https://complexly.info/Permianshirt

Scientists have been trying to solve the mystery of why plate tectonics works the way it does for over a hundred years. And they might have just uncovered a key to cracking it.

*****
PBS Member Stations rely on viewers like you. To support your local station, go to http://to.pbs.org/DonateEons
*****

Eons is a production of Complexly for PBS Digital Studios.

Super special thanks to the following Patreon patrons for helping make Eons possible:
Duane Westhoff, Morgan, Ruth Orr, Bart & Elke van Iersel - De Jong, Karen Farrell, Mark Talbott-Williams, Jonathan Rust, Irene Wood, Mary Tevington, Pope John XII, Aaditya Mehta, Gizmo, Marco Narajos, AllPizzasArePersonal, Stephen Patterson, Walter Ray-Dulany, Yu Mei, Alex Hackman, Jason Rostoker, Travis Bauer, Nomi Alchin, Lianne Lairmore, Collin Dutrow, Hillary Ryde-Collins, Albert Folsom, John H. Austin, Jr., Randall George, Kevin Lacson, Dan Caffee, Jeff Graham, Nick Ryhajlo

If you'd like to support the channel, head over to http://patreon.com/eons and pledge for some cool rewards!

Want to follow Eons elsewhere on the internet?
Facebook - https://www.facebook.com/eonsshow
Instagram - https://www.instagram.com/eonsshow/
Bluesky - https://bsky.app/profile/pbseons.bsky.social
#Eons #platetectonics 

References:
https://docs.google.com/document/d/1yI_7PzS3CQAirHcoU1r8tNQNTqfBXrNmrWC3oIHHuxw/edit?usp=sharing]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Building Modern Software at Scale: Architectural Principles • Randy Shoup &amp; Ch. Humble • GOTO 2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_ZvwRJnSsQ4</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/_ZvwRJnSsQ4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 13:00:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This interview was recorded for GOTO Unscripted. #GOTOcon #GOTOunscripted
https://gotopia.tech

Read the full transcription of this interview here:
https://gotopia.tech/articles/362

Randy Shoup - SVP Engineering at Thrive Market
Charles Humble - Freelance Techie, Podcaster, Editor, Author & Consultant

RESOURCES
Randy
https://bsky.app/profile/randyshoup.bsky.social
https://medium.com/@randyshoup
https://x.com/randyshoup
https://github.com/randyshoup-thrive
https://www.linkedin.com/in/randyshoup

Charles
https://bsky.app/profile/charleshumble.bsky.social
https://linkedin.com/in/charleshumble
https://mastodon.social/@charleshumble
https://conissaunce.com

Links
https://se-radio.net/2008/09/episode-109-ebays-architecture-principles-with-randy-shoup
https://youtu.be/9Q7GANXn02k
https://youtu.be/suOjtOFfyZg
https://youtu.be/m2ZlX1je3as
https://youtu.be/GBTdnfD6s5Q
https://youtu.be/5OjqD-ow8GE
https://youtu.be/whi0T1a4cWU
https://youtu.be/P_6eDL1aqtA
https://youtu.be/9vS7TbgirgY
https://youtu.be/JP3tWboFozY
https://youtu.be/OzCE4m9ERvU
https://youtu.be/8oqT5tjqf-0
https://youtu.be/TMQCiX5wUVU
https://youtu.be/FPfjHon2tFY
https://youtu.be/AYUNI2Pm6_w
https://youtu.be/-5kK50d-duc
https://youtu.be/xTUePYLtsyE
https://youtu.be/y1SpwCiRoPY
https://youtu.be/sjc8UZvlWYQ
https://youtu.be/xDuwrtwYHu8
https://youtu.be/es3DNd5Qipg
https://youtu.be/BIuBnLTMkfQ
https://youtu.be/w008iz_UwDk
https://youtu.be/DeoGKK7cG5Y

DESCRIPTION
Charles Humble sits down with veteran tech leader Randy Shoup, now SVP of Engineering at Thrive Market.
Randy discusses Thrive Market’s evolution from a 10-year-old monolith to a microservices architecture, emphasizing domain-driven design and agile scaling. Drawing on his experiences at eBay and other tech giants, he explains when to adopt microservices and the importance of continuous delivery and platform engineering for boosting productivity.

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
01:00 Thrive Market & Randy's career journey
04:32 Evolving architecture: From monolith to microservices
10:53 Microservices: When (and why) to break apart your monolith
15:08 The relationship between organizational scaling & microservices
19:17 How eBay doubled engineering productivity
29:01 Balancing platform engineering effort
38:11 Building eBay today: Modern architecture & cloud tools
45:21 Evolution of architectural principles over 20 years
52:47 Outro

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Sam Newman • Monolith to Microservices • https://amzn.to/2Nml96E
Sam Newman • Building Resilient Distributed Systems • https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/building-resilient-distributed/9781098163532
Dave Farley & Jez Humble • Continuous Delivery • https://amzn.to/3ocIHwd
Forsgren, Humble & Kim • Accelerate • https://amzn.to/367RI5o
Gene Kim, Jez Humble, Nicole Forsgren, Patrick Debois & John Willis • The DevOps Handbook • https://amzn.to/3C0Rj0C
Gregor Hohpe • Platform Strategy • https://amzn.to/4cxfYdb
Ford, Parsons, Kua & Sadalage • Building Evolutionary Architectures 2nd Edition • https://amzn.to/3lqr5Q8
Simon Brown • Software Architecture for Developers Vol. 2 • https://leanpub.com/visualising-software-architecture
Michael Feathers • Working Effectively with Legacy Code • https://amzn.to/3ZFQoMU
Michael Nygard • Release It! 2nd Edition • https://amzn.to/3WJeKV8

https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com
https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#SoftwareArchitecture #Microservices #Monolith #MonolithToMicroservices #eBayArchitecture #ContinuousDelivery #DevOps #DORAMetrics #PlatformEngineering #PlatformTeams #EngineeringProductivity #Change #RandyShoup #CharlesHumble

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The DEVASTATING first attack of Desert Storm</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JXxiGfVfQzk</link><author>Imperial War Museums</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/JXxiGfVfQzk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 12:00:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3uAjWoLZ4bSi6qI9SjALxA">Imperial War Museums</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#desertstorm #history #gulfwar #iraq #iwm]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How to balance paying debt vs. investing</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a9vPm615xnY</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/a9vPm615xnY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The simple math behind paying off debt versus investing.

This video is presented by Robinhood. Our sponsor has no editorial influence over how we report our stories, but their support makes videos like these possible.

When you get to a place financially where you can begin to start saving, rather than living paycheck to paycheck, a big question often comes up: ”Should I pay off my debt or invest in the stock market?” There’s no simple answer, but there’s a simple rule of thumb that can help you decide what to do with this money to have the best financial outcome in the long run. 

The first place to look is the interest rate on your debt and see if it’s below 7%, the rate of return you can conservatively expect from investing in an index fund, like the S&P 500. If your debt — like a mortgage or a student loan — falls below 7%, it is usually mathematically more beneficial to invest in the stock market while you pay down the debt by its minimum payments. The logic being: You’ll likely earn more interest by investing than your debt will accrue in that time. 

Higher interest rate debt, like credit card debt, should almost always be eliminated as soon as possible, since you are statistically unlikely to see a rate of return from investing past 7 to 10% annually. And of course, investing always comes with risk. So the most secure bet is always to work toward being debt-free.

Further reading: 

How to Prioritize Retirement Savings vs. Debt Payoff, Bill Fay
https://www.debt.org/retirement/prioritize-savings-vs-payoff/

Should you pay down debt or invest?, Fidelity
https://www.fidelity.com/learning-center/personal-finance/pay-down-debt-vs-invest

Debt Destroyer, a US government online tool to help make a plan to eliminate debt
https://finred.usalearning.gov/debt-destroyer-calculator/debt-destroyer-calculator.html

Note: The title of this video has been updated
Previous title: When it's okay to wait to pay off debt

Subscribe to our channel! http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on Facebook: http://goo.gl/U2g06o
Or Twitter: http://goo.gl/XFrZ5H]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dubai’s Billion-Dollar Crypto Underworld</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QQzxiKfyddg</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/QQzxiKfyddg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 08:00:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In early 2024, the US charged cryptocurrency entrepreneur Sam Lee with running a Ponzi and pyramid scheme called HyperVerse, alleging he defrauded people of $2 billion. But instead of facing trial in the US, Lee now lives in Dubai, where he’s pitching new crypto products. 

Lee denies any wrongdoing. But crypto industry experts, alleged victims and online “scam hunters” are raising questions about whether regulators in the United Arab Emirates are doing enough to combat crypto fraud as Dubai seeks to position itself as a hub of finance and technology. 

Read more about the story on Bloomberg:
https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2024-12-05/dubai-s-alleged-crypto-scams-are-raking-in-billions?sref=omvmmwIg?utm_medium=social&utm_source=youtube&utm_campaign=originals&utm_content=article

On a scorching July day in Dubai, Sam Lee was inside a climate-controlled wine bar, sipping a glass of chilled red, looking untouchable. Near the beginning of the year, US authorities announced that they’d charged Lee with conspiracy to commit securities fraud and wire fraud. They alleged that, as the co-founder of a company called HyperVerse, he’d orchestrated a cryptocurrency scam that bilked investors around the world for almost $2 billion. HyperVerse had promised returns as high as 1% a day via cutting-edge blockchain-based strategies, but according to the US Department of Justice and the Securities and Exchange Commission, it was just an old-fashioned Ponzi scheme. Lee has denied wrongdoing.

0:00 The two sides of Sam Lee
2:06  HyperVerse’s collapse
5:58 The Crypto Ponzi Scheme Avenger
9:14 Dubai’s crypto underworld
14:21 Detained in Dubai
17:07 The new Sam Lee

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for $1.99/month for the first 3 months: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals

Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg Quicktake for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Vampires in Poland? | Secrets of the Dead | PBS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wmiB69bxiUA</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wmiB69bxiUA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 22:00:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Watch more: https://to.pbs.org/3mHxfbj | #SecretsDeadPBS
In this chilling discovery, experts uncover the grave of a 17th-century woman in Poland, buried with a sickle around her neck and a padlock on her ankles to prevent her from rising as a vampire. This mysterious woman may have been buried this way due to her unconventional lifestyle and suspected undiagnosed illness, which led locals to fear her as an undead threat.

This program is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Subscribe to the PBS channel for more clips:  https://www.youtube.com/PBS/

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS App: https://to.pbs.org/2QbtzhR

FOLLOW US:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/PBS/
X: https://twitter.com/PBS/
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/PBS/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@pbs
Threads: https://www.threads.net/@pbs

Secrets of the Dead on YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/@secretsofthedead

#SecretsoftheDead #archeology #vampires #graves

Secrets of the Dead
Part detective story, part true-life drama, @secretsofthedead unearths evidence from around the world, challenging prevailing ideas and throwing fresh light on unexplained events.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How Have History&apos;s Trade Wars Played Out?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8PhEo1o-wDo</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/8PhEo1o-wDo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 22:00:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA["Trade wars are good, and easy to win," writes U.S President Donald Trump on Twitter. However, Trump is quite alone with this opinion in the professional world. History has taught us that trade wars are not "easy" or "good." Nevertheless, experts fear that the conflicts Trump has instigated will turn into a tangible trade war - and to the point of striking parallels in history. What led to the outbreak of trade wars in the past? Who is the winner, and who will lose in the battle for advantages in global trade? What really stands behind the astonishing renaissance of customs barriers and protectionism?

Do you love uncovering the past, exploring historic sites, and venturing to distant lands? Join History Hit today and stream hundreds of exclusive documentaries, with new releases every week. Plus, enjoy ad-free access to our podcast network for even more history every week.

Head over to https://eu1.hubs.ly/H0gFQRz0 to secure your free trial, and embark on your journey through history!

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>🥧Pi r squared</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kd27hxb8s4E</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/kd27hxb8s4E?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 19:53:24 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#PiDay is almost here!

Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Exploring the Mysteries of Prehistoric Scotland | Full Series</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uLcIAsbbQXE</link><author>History Hit</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/uLcIAsbbQXE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 18:00:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ">History Hit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Tristan Hughes goes on a road trip of a lifetime to discover more about the mysteries of prehistoric Scotland.

In Part one, Tristan heads to Orkney to investigate its astonishing 5,000 year old Stone Age remains. 

In Part two, Tristan sees the beautiful carvings of adult red deer, the first animal representations in Scotland. This is just one of the remarkable finds in one of the most extraordinary prehistoric landscapes in Scotland: the magical and mysterious Kilmartin Glen.

In Part three, Tristan ventures across Scotland to investigate prehistoric skyscrapers - brochs.

Discover the past on History Hit with ad-free exclusive podcasts and documentaries released weekly presented by world renowned historians Dan Snow, Suzannah Lipscomb, Lucy Worsely, Mary Beard and more. Watch, listen and read history wherever you are, whenever you want it. Available on all devices: Apple TV, Amazon Prime Video, Android TV, Samsung Smart TV, Roku, Xbox, Chromecast, and iOs & Android.

We're offering a special discount to History Hit for our subscribers, get 50% off your first 3 months with code YOUTUBE: https://www.historyhit.com/subscription/?utm_source=youtube&utm_medium=description&utm_campaign=YouTube2024

#historyhit #prehistoric #scotland]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Eons Patreon Appreciation Livestream with Michelle, Blake, Kallie, and Gabriel!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V731Q2_4kwQ</link><author>PBS Eons</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/V731Q2_4kwQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 17:07:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzR-rom72PHN9Zg7RML9EbA">PBS Eons</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[It's Patron Appreciation Month at Eons, and you're invited! To celebrate, join us for a livestream on March 27 with our hosts, to talk Eons and take a special tour of Kallie's office! 

Become a member at Patreon.com/eons at the Paleozoic level or above by March 31 and receive the very first Eons trading card! Plus, show your love for Eons and the Permian Era with our new t-shirt: https://complexly.info/Permianshirt]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Sun isn&apos;t as big or as bright as you think! #ThinkAgain #Shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u0xUb23YHPM</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/u0xUb23YHPM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 17:01:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">BBC Earth Science</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Best of Earth Science: http://bit.ly/EarthLabOriginals 
Best of BBC Earth: http://bit.ly/TheBestOfBBCEarthVideos 

This is a channel from BBC Studios who help fund new BBC programmes. Service information and feedback: http://bbcworldwide.com/vod-feedback--contact-details.aspx]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What it&apos;s like to be a working homeless person in Germany | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gPd3OF4w-ZY</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/gPd3OF4w-ZY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 17:00:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Working daily to sleep on the street at night? That’s a reality for thousands in Germany, who despite having a job cannot find a place to live. 

Attila Kokas works for the Berlin City Mission as a gardener. Denny Wagner is a cook. At an emergency shelter he prepares food for homeless people. For a few months now, Denny has been spending nights in a small, simple hut with no electricity. Attila sleeps on the street, before he makes his way to work in the early hours. Despite having jobs, both men have been unable to find an affordable apartment in Berlin. They share their fate with quite a few people in Germany. In larger cities in particular, the housing market is tight. This hits people emerging from homelessness and earning low wages especially hard. How can they get away from being without a roof?

00:00 Intro
00:50 Denny: a homeless cook
02:10 Attila: a gardener without a home
04:13 At work with Denny in the emergency shelter
06:01 Attila is hoping for an apartment
07:00 Homelessness in Germany
08:52 Denny’s shelter
11:01 Attila’s new abode
11:54 Denny views the future

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #reporter #germany 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/dwdochindi
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How green is green energy? | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r7_cQDGId-Y</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/r7_cQDGId-Y?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:00:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[If we want a truly sustainable energy future, we need to rethink how we source, use, and recycle these vital resources. The solution isn’t just in greener technology, it’s in how we sustain it. Lithium is powering our world, but at what cost? Can we make lithium recycling truly sustainable before it's too late? 

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs
______

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>#IoannisKolaxis on what #SoftwareEngineers can do to help prevent #ClimateChange</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NQusBKCyTiI</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/NQusBKCyTiI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out the full version on our YouTube channel now! #GOTOcon #GOTOams #Sustainability #SustainableSoftware #SustainableProgramming #CarbonEfficiency #Efficiency #HumanFactor #IoannisKolaxis #Atos #DataNetworks #Containers #Decarbonization #Serverless #AWSLambda #AzureFunctions #GoogleCloudFunctions #GreenCloud #GreenComputing #GreenCoding #Programming #GreenSoftware #Viral #ViralShorts #GOTO

Full version available here:
https://youtu.be/NjrObiE6_tE

Ioannis Kolaxis - Software Architect / Distinguished Expert at Atos @ioanniskolaxis 

RECOMMENDED BOOK
Ioannis Kolaxis • 101 Green Software • https://www.kolaxis.dev/book-green-software
Mehdi Khosrow-Pour • Green Computing Strategies for Competitive Advantage and Business Sustainability • https://amzn.to/2YXbI7j
Lässig, Kersting & Morik • Computational Sustainability • https://amzn.to/3APBW8r
Zbigniew H. Gontar • Smart Grid Analytics for Sustainability and Urbanization • https://amzn.to/3pkRVsS

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How AI helps Hollywood de-age actors</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r4AsZYIn6Ug</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/r4AsZYIn6Ug?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 12:01:14 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[It takes a lot of training data.

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

In 2025, Tom Hanks is 67 years old. Yet, in his latest film Here (directed by Robert Zemeckis), he's convincingly transformed to appear as young as 18, and aged even beyond his current years. And the effect actually looks …. good! Here's how they do it.

Vox is on a mission is to help everyone, regardless of income or status, understand our complicated world so that we can all help shape it. Part of that mission is keeping our work free. 

You can help us do that by making a gift: http://www.vox.com/give-now

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Unboxing Epomaker Cypher 98 &amp; Carbon60 keyboards!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kPZ4jAiNNiw</link><author>Chyrosran22</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/kPZ4jAiNNiw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 06:00:34 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCD0y51PJfvkZNe3y3FR5riw">Chyrosran22</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Get them here: 
https://epomaker.com/products/epomaker-cypher-96
https://epomaker.com/products/epomaker-carbon60
Today we look at a duo of cool keyboards; a modern, near-fullsize with a calculator module embedded, including screen, and a board made out of actual carbon fibre! Epomaker always come up with funky stuff, should be interesting ^^ . 

Intro by Kyle Carter
Outro by Facundo Cabanne

My keyboard reviews: http://bit.ly/1TbOtft
My switch teardowns: http://bit.ly/2C1QGHz
My TOP X videos: http://bit.ly/2FmpZfd
My XL typing demos: https://bit.ly/2OoAW3w
My tutorials and featurettes: https://bit.ly/2OrkLUh
My unboxing videos: https://bit.ly/2TSrr0m

I'm Thomas and I do videos and reviews on mechanical keyboards ranging from the most sickening modern RGB gaming keyboards to vintage hardware relics, or sometimes keycaps or keyswitches ranging from Cherry MX to Alps SKCM to IBM buckling springs and anything in between.

Follow me on Twitter for updates on my keyboard videos! https://twitter.com/chyrosran22]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Uganda - Protheses for a new life | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TTNdFaHwjyM</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/TTNdFaHwjyM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 9 Mar 2025 17:00:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[For people with disabilities in Uganda, there’s little medical care available. It’s often a long way to travel to see a doctor, and treatment is expensive. But an organization from Germany is providing those affected with orthopedic aids, as well as training specialists.

In Uganda, people with disabilities not only often live in great poverty, there’s also hardly any medical care available to them. For more than 10 years now, an organization from Usingen in the German state of Hesse has been providing people with prostheses and other orthopedic aids. In the small town of Kiyunga near the capital Kampala, ProUganda has set up a center with a modern orthopedic workshop and treatment rooms.
But not everyone can get there: The roads are uneven and it’s difficult for poor families to get to Kiyunga with their children. That’s why the team travels to rural areas in minibuses. In the trunk: wheelchairs, some delivered second-hand from Germany, some bought with donations.
The film accompanies members of the aid organization as they work with patients in Kiyunga, in the workshop and on missions in the region.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #uganda #medical #africa 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/dwdochindi
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>From Crisis to Innovation: The Steam Engine That Changed Everything | BBC Earth Science</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hQfVI5WmDIs</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hQfVI5WmDIs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 9 Mar 2025 16:00:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">BBC Earth Science</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[What if we told you that a simple plastic bottle experiment reveals the science behind one of history’s most important inventions, created by Thomas Newcomen in 1712?

#SteamEngine #IndustrialRevolution #Innovation #DrHelenCzerski

Best of Earth Science: http://bit.ly/EarthLabOriginals 
Best of BBC Earth: http://bit.ly/TheBestOfBBCEarthVideos 

This Clip is taken from the BBC Series 'From Ice to Fire: The Incredible Science of Temperature'

This is a channel from BBC Studios who help fund new BBC programmes. Service information and feedback: http://bbcworldwide.com/vod-feedback--contact-details.aspx]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Germany&apos;s Historic Debt Deal!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D3uOXXGjb6g</link><author>Patrick Boyle</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/D3uOXXGjb6g?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 9 Mar 2025 14:30:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCASM0cgfkJxQ1ICmRilfHLw">Patrick Boyle</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://surfshark.com/boyle for 4 extra months of Surfshark

European markets rallied sharply this week as German borrowing costs soared after the country’s new leaders announced a historic deal to loosen its “debt brake” rule to boost spending on defense.

The interest rate on German government bonds saw their biggest daily increase since October 1998.

The Dax 30 index, which tracks the largest German companies, rose by 3.5% as stock prices also leapt in other European markets amid hopes that a massive boost in European spending on defense and infrastructure would kickstart the region’s lagging economy.

Patrick's Books:
Statistics For The Trading Floor:  https://amzn.to/3eerLA0
Derivatives For The Trading Floor:  https://amzn.to/3cjsyPF
Corporate Finance:  https://amzn.to/3fn3rvC 

Ways To Support The Channel
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/PatrickBoyleOnFinance
Buy Me a Coffee: https://www.buymeacoffee.com/patrickboyle

Visit our website: https://www.onfinance.org
Follow Patrick on Twitter Here: https://bsky.app/profile/pboyle.bsky.social

Business Inquiries ➡️ sponsors@onfinance.org

Patrick Boyle On Finance Podcast:
Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/7uhrWlDvxzy9hLoW0EYf0b
Apple: https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/patrick-boyle-on-finance/id1547740313
Google Podcasts: https://tinyurl.com/62862nve

Join this channel to support making this content:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCASM0cgfkJxQ1ICmRilfHLw/join]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Timeline TV: 1991 - Everything That Happened In TV In The Year 1991</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SWc3J7bKWLE</link><author>Weird History</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/SWc3J7bKWLE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 9 Mar 2025 14:00:33 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCc-N24Y5OA0gqbjBwe1ttfA">Weird History</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Today on Weird History we are taking a deep dive into all there was to watch on TV in the year 1991!  The Jerry Springer Show made an inauspicious debut, Adam Sandler got his start on Saturday Night Live, and several iconic sitcoms came to an end. What were you doing in 1991? What were YOUR favorite shows on TV? Let us know in the comments!

Be sure to subscribe to the Weird History Newsletter: https://bit.ly/WeirdHistoryNews

#1991 #timelineTV #weirdhistory]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ant Farm Entropy: Sugar Powered Encryption • Suz Hinton • YOW! 2024</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ymJsJkxDIbo</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ymJsJkxDIbo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 9 Mar 2025 13:01:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This presentation was recorded at YOW! Australia 2024. #GOTOcon #YOW
https://yowcon.com

Suz Hinton - Senior Software Engineer at CrowdStrike @suzhinton9821 @Noopkat 

RESOURCES
https://bsky.app/profile/noopkat.fragile.systems
https://github.com/noopkat
https://www.linkedin.com/in/susanmhinton
https://www.twitch.tv/noopkat

Links
https://blog.cloudflare.com/randomness-101-lavarand-in-production
https://lavarand.org
patentimages.storage.googleapis.com/6d/9b/ee/d30a9570cd8af3/US5732138.pdf
https://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/document?repid=rep1&type=pdf&doi=95d5042fc5963d387563247166b7f904fb1153c8

ABSTRACT
Randomness is essential for important applications such as the encryption of information. We know computers are bad at generating randomness, therefore much effort has been put into finding strategies to do this reliably and securely. These strategies can range from clever, to complex, to just outright silly.

In this talk, we'll cover a research project that aims to answer the question of whether an ant colony can serve as a source for seeding OpenSSL's random number generator. The process, challenges, and findings will be candidly discussed, with something in this presentation for everyone to take away. [...]

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
01:50 Agenda
03:28 Pseudo Random Number Generators (PRNG)
09:54 Sources of "randomness" & chaos systems
14:36 Research into a potentially useful chaos system
19:34 Biological, hardware & software considerations
19:42 Ants
22:50 Hardware
29:18 Software
39:21 Results
40:38 Next steps
42:16 Why do this?
44:30 Outro

Download slides and read the full abstract here:
https://yowcon.com/brisbane-2024/sessions/3512

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Liz Rice • Container Security • https://amzn.to/3oU4iJe
Liz Rice • Kubernetes Security • https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/kubernetes-security/9781492039075
Aaron Parecki • OAuth 2.0 Simplified • https://amzn.to/2A3IMOf
Aaron Parecki • OAuth 2.0 Servers • https://amzn.to/3ecHEsz
Aaron Parecki • The Little Book of OAuth 2.0 RFCs • https://amzn.to/3i7qnlC
Erdal Ozkaya • Cybersecurity: The Beginner's Guide • https://amzn.to/2T6OIj3

https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com
https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#Encryption #ChaosSystem #Privacy #Cloudflare #Lavarand #Security #Cybersecurity #Cryptography #SoftwareEngineering #PRNG #OpenSSL #Programming #SuzHinton #noopkat #YOWcon

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Coughs and Sneezes Spread Diseases!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BYhfHL5VaNQ</link><author>Imperial War Museums</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/BYhfHL5VaNQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 9 Mar 2025 12:00:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3uAjWoLZ4bSi6qI9SjALxA">Imperial War Museums</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Second World War British Ministry of Information cartoon newsreel warning people to use a handkerchief to stop the spread of diseases.

Watch the full film on the IWM Film site: https://film.iwmcollections.org.uk/record/40226

#secondworldwar #disease #cartoon]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Could peanut butter cure the Plague? 🥜 #Conservation #Science</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7p0BoFZ_27o</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7p0BoFZ_27o?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 9 Mar 2025 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">BBC Earth Science</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Happiest man alive</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i5Qrt87Ab8U</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/i5Qrt87Ab8U?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 9 Mar 2025 00:52:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Nukes, Submarines &amp; The Cold War: When The World Stood On The Edge Of Nuclear War</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9k2VDBwa-Sw</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/9k2VDBwa-Sw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 8 Mar 2025 22:00:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Play Conflict of Nations for FREE on PC or Mobile:
💥 https://con.onelink.me/kZW6/TIME001
Receive 13K GOLD & 1 month premium subscription, only available for the next 30 days!

The Cold War: When nuclear weapons kept the entire world on the edge of Mutually Assured Destruction. As Russia, China and the USA flex their military muscles on the global stage today, we take a close look at the last time we were threatened by the might of world superpowers.

Do you love uncovering the past, exploring historic sites, and venturing to distant lands? Join History Hit today and stream hundreds of exclusive documentaries, with new releases every week. Plus, enjoy ad-free access to our podcast network for even more history every week.

Head over to https://eu1.hubs.ly/H0gFQRz0 to secure your free trial, and embark on your journey through history.

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The coronavirus pandemic and its consequences | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0oVToMh110U</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0oVToMh110U?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 8 Mar 2025 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Covid-19 was officially declared a pandemic on 11 March 2020. The deadly disease spread so quickly around the world that it could not be contained with known measures. It was the beginning of a two-year state of emergency.

To many, it felt like something out of a disaster movie. This film relates how a number of people across Europe dealt with the crisis. Initially, the world was gripped by fear of this unknown virus that spread through the air that we breathe. In countries like Italy, the number of deaths rose so fast that medical personnel and undertakers were quickly overwhelmed. 

The public was sympathetic and supportive. People came out onto their balconies every evening to applaud the efforts of hospital staff. They were clapping for people like Carlo Mosca, a doctor in Brescia, Italy, who spent the first few months of the pandemic in hospital almost non-stop, caring for patients. Many of them died alone, as social distancing rules meant visitors were not allowed. Carlo Mosca didn’t see his family for months so as not to infect them.

When the first wave of the virus subsided, governments across Europe eased restrictions again. After a brief respite, further waves and restrictions followed, but by now, people were growing accustomed to the changes in their daily lives. However, things took a dramatic turn for Carlo Mosca. He was arrested in January 2021 and accused of murdering two patients with coronavirus to free up beds. Carlo Mosca had to remain under house arrest during the trial - while outside, life seemed to be returning to normal.

By now there was a general sense of relief - but it was short-lived. The number of infections shot up again in the fall. Many countries, including France, went back into lockdown. The film follows Aurélie Rhumeur as she and her husband Yves Chuop try to keep their Paris pharmacy running, home-school their daughter Cassandre and provide emotional support while keeping their own fears under control. Like all the protagonists in the documentary, Aurélie films herself - thus providing deep insight into a family life that is slowly disintegrating due to isolation and uncertainty over how long the state of emergency will last.

As the pandemic entered its second year, no one was applauding anymore. Expressions of solidarity gave way to those of frustration and anger. People across Europe took to the streets in anti-government protests, as conspiracy myths spread. Emotions were running high and only slightly eased by the development of a coronavirus vaccination. People were questioning the price they paid for efforts at protection against a deadly virus. Was it too high?

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #coronavirus #pandemic 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/dwdochindi
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Impunity of femicides in Mexico | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZWEeicP1oDY</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ZWEeicP1oDY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 8 Mar 2025 14:00:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Mexico has been in the global spotlight due to the high incidence of violence against women, particularly femicide – the gender-based killing of women. It is estimated that around 10 women and girls are killed every day by intimate partners or other family members. 

Another alarming statistic is the impunity rate of these crimes. Only 2% of cases end in a criminal sentence and only one in 10 victims dares to report their aggressor. 

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #8M 
______

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Java&apos;s Hidden Gems: Tools &amp; Libraries • Johan Janssen • YOW! 2024</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RlCpgSoOX6I</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/RlCpgSoOX6I?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 8 Mar 2025 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This presentation was recorded at YOW! Australia 2024. #GOTOcon #YOW
https://yowcon.com

Johan Janssen - Software Architect at ASML

RESOURCES
https://bsky.app/profile/johanjanssen.bsky.social
https://mastodon.social/@johanjanssen
https://twitter.com/johanjanssen42
https://github.com/johanjanssen

ABSTRACT
This session is a whirlwind tour of many lesser known, but very interesting, Java tools and libraries. We'll have a sneak peak at dozens of tools to improve security, builds, architecture, tests and other areas. After this session you'll surely have learned something new, which you can further investigate whenever you want to apply it. [...]

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
00:42 Topics
01:18 Software architecture
03:45 Testing
19:29 Implementation
33:15 Security
36:30 Builds
42:46 Outro

Download slides and read the full abstract here:
https://yowcon.com/brisbane-2024/sessions/3519

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Thomas Vitale • Cloud Native Spring in Action • https://amzn.to/3kLu1ns
Nicolai Parlog • The Java Module System • https://amzn.to/3xFggR4
Monica Beckwith • JVM Performance Engineering • https://amzn.to/3zuJ7Ig
Trisha Gee, Kathy Sierra & Bert Bates • Head First Java • https://amzn.to/3k59BJ6
Trisha Gee & Kevlin Henney • 97 Things Every Java Programmer Should Know • https://amzn.to/3kiTwJJ

https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com
https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#Java #JavaProgramming #JavaTools #JavaLibraries #ArchUnit #Awaitability #Pitest #EqualsVerifier #TimeFold #ApacheSpark #OWASP #Passay #Programing #SoftwareEngineering #JohanJanssen

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Strange Way We&apos;re Still Fighting The Black Death | Save Our Species | BBC Earth Science</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qMD_Dpvy3TU</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/qMD_Dpvy3TU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 8 Mar 2025 12:01:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">BBC Earth Science</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Black Plague is still around today, and whilst it's incredibly rare that it affects humans, it can be a huge threat to animals. The good news is there is a vaccine, and much like getting your dog to take a tablet, peanut butter seems to be the key to getting animals to eat it.

#Vaccines #TheBlackPlague #Conservation

Best of Earth Science: http://bit.ly/EarthLabOriginals 
Best of BBC Earth: http://bit.ly/TheBestOfBBCEarthVideos 

This is a channel from BBC Studios who help fund new BBC programmes. Service information and feedback: http://bbcworldwide.com/vod-feedback--contact-details.aspx]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Rise and Fall of Terrorgram (trailer) | FRONTLINE</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_xydLuigooY</link><author>FRONTLINE PBS | Official</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/_xydLuigooY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Mar 2025 22:23:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3ScyryU9Oy9Wse3a8OAmYQ">FRONTLINE PBS | Official</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[FRONTLINE and ProPublica investigate how an online network known as Terrorgram spread extremism and violence. The documentary traces the rise of a global community of white supremacists and the anonymous, loosely moderated platforms used to spread hate and promote terror attacks.

This journalism is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station here: https://www.pbs.org/donate​

Subscribe on YouTube: http://bit.ly/1BycsJW​
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/frontlinepbs​
Twitter: https://twitter.com/frontlinepbs​
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/frontline

FRONTLINE is produced at GBH in Boston and is broadcast nationwide on PBS. Funding for FRONTLINE is provided through the support of PBS viewers and by the Corporation for Public Broadcasting. Additional support for FRONTLINE is provided by the Abrams Foundation, Park Foundation, the John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, the Heising-Simons Foundation, and the FRONTLINE Journalism Fund, with major support from Jon and Jo Ann Hagler on behalf of the Jon L. Hagler Foundation, and additional support from Koo and Patricia Yuen.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How CLOSE are we to fusion energy? 😂</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uuqA3F-7vpw</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/uuqA3F-7vpw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Mar 2025 20:04:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>This guy met DaBaby</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8Nv1Y1GLlis</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/8Nv1Y1GLlis?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Mar 2025 18:27:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Is This the Scariest Sound in Space?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rqSwTC0UtRI</link><author>Astrum</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/rqSwTC0UtRI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Mar 2025 18:00:57 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-9b7aDP6ZN0coj9-xFnrtw">Astrum</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The universe is far from silent. An eerie symphony echoes through the cosmos, lurking in the depths of space. Prepare for a spine-chilling journey through the haunting sounds of black holes, comets, and the mysterious rings of Saturn. 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

0:00 The Scariest Sounds in Space
2:32 The Sound of Saturn’s Rings
6:09 The Sound of a Comet 
8:43 The Sound of a Supermassive Black Hole
12:36 The Sound of Black Holes Colliding 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Astrum Podcast: https://www.buzzsprout.com/2250635/share
Astrum Infographic Artwork: https://electrify.art/collections/astrum 
Astrum Displate Posters: https://astrumspace.info/Displates 
Astrum Merch: https://astrum-shop.fourthwall.com/

Join us on the Astrum discord: https://discord.gg/TKw8Hpvtv8 

SUBSCRIBE for more videos about space and astronomy. 
Subscribe! http://goo.gl/WX4iMN 
Facebook! http://goo.gl/uaOlWW 
Twitter! http://goo.gl/VCfejs 

A huge thanks to our Patreons who help make these videos possible. Sign-up here: https://bit.ly/4aiJZNF 

Astrum Spanish: https://www.youtube.com/@astrumespanol 
Astrum Portuguese: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChn_-OwvV63mr1yeUGvH-BQ 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Credits
Writer: Julia Masselos
Editor: Nick Shishkin
Thumbnail Designer: Peter Sheppard
Channel Manager: Georgina Brenner
Executive Producer: Raquel Taylor
Creator of Astrum: Alex McColgan

With special thanks to:
NASA/ESO/ESA

#astrum #spacesounds #astronomy]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>