<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Podcasts</title><link>https://konrad.website/liveboat-github-runner/</link><description></description><item><title>Thomas Flint - Can God do Everything?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DkxJZOW7Dxg</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/DkxJZOW7Dxg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 16:00:24 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Get access to over 5,000 videos by signing up for a free Closer To Truth membership: https://closertotruth.com/register/

If God can do everything, what would this mean? Can God make a circle square, a bachelor married, 2+2=5? Can God make it the case that God does not exist? How about change the past? Or create creatures with robust free will? If God is in any way limited, does that contradict the notion of God as omnipotent or as a ‘perfect being’?

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Thomas Flint is an American philosopher and Professor Emeritus of Philosophy at the University of Notre Dame, known for his work on philosophy of religion. He served as Editor of Faith and Philosophy for eight years and was the Director of the Notre Dame Center for Philosophy of Religion for six years, after having served as Associate Director for 18 years, during Alvin Plantinga’s time as Director.

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Stuart Hameroff on Christof Koch, AI, and Consciousness</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/KGjoS0ADafE</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/KGjoS0ADafE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 20:00:24 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[We sat down with Stuart Hameroff during the Festival of Consciousness to discuss quantum biology, AI, and solving the problem of consciousness. He discusses his work with neuroscientist Christof Koch and the theory of neuro-computationalism at the time of AI and LLMs.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Quayshawn Spencer - Philosophy of Medicine &amp; Healthcare</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2lfr1VV-kM0</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/2lfr1VV-kM0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 16:00:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you get your podcasts: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Can philosophy contribute to medicine and healthcare? For example, philosophy can help clarify the concept of cancer, its nature, kinds and variations. Philosophy can also help discern different levels or qualities of healthcare for different groups.

Follow Closer To Truth on Instagram for updates, announcements, and videos: https://shorturl.at/EzYo9

Quayshawn Spencer is the Robert S. Blank Presidential Associate Professor of Philosophy and Undergraduate Chair at the University of Pennsylvania.

Make a donation to Closer To Truth to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions without the need for paywalls: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Han shot first (Friends)</title><link>https://changelog.com/friends/128</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/friends/128/changelog--friends-128.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Our ol’ friend, Brett Cannon, is back to talk all things Python. But first! Star Wars, Machete Order, Lost, Babylon 5, Game of Thrones, Murderbot, Ted Lasso, Project Hail Mary, David Attenborough, perpetual voice rights, and the AI uncanny valley.Changelog++ members save 4 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!Namespace – Speed up your development and testing workflows using your existing tools. (Much) faster GitHub actions, Docker builds, and more. At an unbeatable price.
Tiger Data – Postgres for Developers, devices, and agents The data platform trusted by hundreds of thousands from IoT to Web3 to AI and more.
Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps close to your users — global Anycast load-balancing, zero-configuration private networking, hardware isolation, and instant WireGuard VPN connections. Push-button deployments that scale to thousands of instances. Check out the speedrun to get started in minutes.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2454 - Robert Malone, MD</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qFwiXyZHYbU</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/qFwiXyZHYbU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:00:57 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Robert W. Malone, MD, MS, is a virologist and immunologist and an original inventor of mRNA delivery and vaccination as a technology, DNA vaccination, and multiple non-viral DNA and RNA/mRNA platform delivery technologies. He serves on the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices and is the author of multiple books, the most recent of which is “PsyWar: Enforcing the New World Order,” co-written with his wife, Dr. Jill Glasspool Malone. The Drs. Malone are the founders of the Malone Institute, which focuses on issues related to government, the biological sciences, and medicine.

https://www.skyhorsepublishing.com/9781510782952/psywar/
https://www.malone.news
https://www.malonebroadcasting.com
https://www.maloneinstitute.org
https://www.rwmalonemd.com

Perplexity: Download the app or ask Perplexity anything at https://pplx.ai/rogan.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Rethinking Notebooks Powered by AI</title><link>https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/mlops/episodes/Rethinking-Notebooks-Powered-by-AI-e3f1smp</link><author>Demetrios</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://anchor.fm/s/174cb1b8/podcast/play/115454105/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2026-1-13%2F418036639-44100-2-1cf8d7510cce7.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:00:33 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mlops.community/">Podcast - MLOps</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ is a Founding Engineer at marimo, working on reinventing Python notebooks as reactive, reproducible, interactive, and Git-friendly environments for data workflows and AI prototyping. He helps build the core marimo notebook platform, pushing its reactive execution model, UI interactivity, and integration with modern development and AI tooling so that notebooks behave like dependable, shareable programs and apps rather than error-prone scratchpads.Vincent Warmerdam joins Demetrios fresh off marimo’s acquisition by Weights & Biases—and makes a bold claim: notebooks as we know them are outdated.They talk Molab (GPU-backed, cloud-hosted notebooks), LLMs that don’t just chat but actually fix your SQL and debug your code, and why most data folks are consuming tools instead of experimenting. Vincent argues we should stop treating notebooks like static scratchpads and start treating them like dynamic apps powered by AI.It’s a conversation about rethinking workflows, reclaiming creativity, and not outsourcing your brain to the model.Vincent is a senior data professional who worked as an engineer, researcher, team lead, and educator in the past. You might know him from tech talks with an attempt to defend common sense over hype in the data space. He is especially interested in understanding algorithmic systems so that one may prevent failure. As such, he has always had a preference to keep calm and check the dataset before flowing tonnes of tensors. He currently works at marimo, where he spends his time rethinking everything related to Python notebooks.~~~~~~~~ ✌️Connect With Us ✌️ ~~~~~~~[00:00] Context in Notebooks[00:24] Acquisition and Team Continuity[04:43] Coding Agent Conference Announcement![05:56] Hyperbolic GPU Cloud Ad[06:54] marimo and W&B Synergies[09:31] marimo Cloud Code Support[12:59] Hardest Code to Generate[16:22] Trough of Disillusionment[20:38] Agent Interaction in Notebooks]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ask Me Anything with Robert Lawrence Kuhn (Part III)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DjtU0WICsbw</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/DjtU0WICsbw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:00:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Robert Lawrence Kuhn answers questions submitted by viewers including: Which Closer To Truth guests have influenced him the most? What are his thoughts on the single greatest threat to humanity? Did the universe have a beginning? And many more.

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2453 - Evan Hafer</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y2SD_z61FRo</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/y2SD_z61FRo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:01:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Evan Hafer is a Special Forces veteran, founder, and executive chairman of Black Rifle Coffee Company, and one of the hosts of the “Black Rifle Coffee Podcast.”

https://www.blackriflecoffee.com
https://www.youtube.com/@BlackRifleCoffeeCompany

Perplexity: Download the app or ask Perplexity anything at https://pplx.ai/rogan.

Go to https://ROKA.com and upgrade your eyewear

This video is sponsored by BetterHelp. Visit https//BetterHelp.com/JRE]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Liad Mudrik - What Living Things are Conscious?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wkuzNzJlq_E</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wkuzNzJlq_E?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:01:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Follow us on X for videos, articles, and polls on life's biggest questions: https://x.com/CloserToTruth

We know we humans are conscious and we strongly suspect higher animals are as well: for example, primates, dogs, cetaceans, whales and dolphins. But how far down the phylogenetic scale does consciousness go? Do fish feel pain? Do insects have awareness? Do bacteria sense? What are the implications?

Sign up for a free Closer To Truth membership to receive exclusives like early access to new episodes: https://closertotruth.com/register/

Professor Liad Mudrik is a researcher at the school of psychological sciences and Sagol school of neuroscience at Tel Aviv University. Her research focuses on conscious experience, its neural mechanisms and functions.

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Gas Town, Beads, and the Rise of Agentic Development with Steve Yegge</title><link>https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2026/02/12/gas-town-beads-and-the-rise-of-agentic-development-with-steve-yegge/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=gas-town-beads-and-the-rise-of-agentic-development-with-steve-yegge</link><author>SEDaily</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.megaphone.fm/SED8427767061.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:00:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="http://softwareengineeringdaily.com/category/all-episodes/exclusive-content/podcast/">Podcast - Software Engineering Daily</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[AI-assisted programming has moved far beyond autocomplete. Large language models are now capable of editing entire codebases, coordinating long-running tasks, and collaborating across multiple systems. As these capabilities mature, the core challenge in software development is shifting away from writing code and toward orchestrating work, managing context, and maintaining shared understanding across fleets of agents.Steve Yegge is a software engineer, writer, and industry veteran whose essays have shaped how many developers think about their work. Over the past year, Steve has been exploring the frontier of agentic software development, building tools like Beads and Gas Town to experiment with multi-agent coordination, shared memory, and AI-driven software workflows.In this episode, Steve joins Kevin Ball to discuss the evolution of AI coding from chat-based assistance to full agent orchestration, the technical and cognitive challenges of managing fleets of agents, how concepts like task graphs and Git-backed ledgers change the nature of work, and what these shifts mean for software teams, tooling, and the future of the industry.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>OpenClaw: The Viral AI Agent that Broke the Internet - Peter Steinberger | Lex Fridman Podcast #491</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YFjfBk8HI5o</link><author>Lex Fridman</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/YFjfBk8HI5o?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 03:07:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSHZKyawb77ixDdsGog4iWA">Podcast - Lex Fridman</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Peter Steinberger is the creator of OpenClaw, an open-source AI agent framework that's the fastest-growing project in GitHub history.
Thank you for listening ❤ Check out our sponsors: https://lexfridman.com/sponsors/ep491-sb
See below for timestamps, transcript, and to give feedback, submit questions, contact Lex, etc.

*Transcript:*
https://lexfridman.com/peter-steinberger-transcript

*CONTACT LEX:*
*Feedback* - give feedback to Lex: https://lexfridman.com/survey
*AMA* - submit questions, videos or call-in: https://lexfridman.com/ama
*Hiring* - join our team: https://lexfridman.com/hiring
*Other* - other ways to get in touch: https://lexfridman.com/contact

*EPISODE LINKS:*
Peter's X: https://x.com/steipete
Peter's GitHub: https://github.com/steipete
Peter's Website: https://steipete.com
Peter's LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/steipete
OpenClaw Website: https://openclaw.ai
OpenClaw GitHub: https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw
OpenClaw Discord: https://discord.gg/openclaw

*SPONSORS:*
To support this podcast, check out our sponsors & get discounts:
*Perplexity:* AI-powered answer engine.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/perplexity-ep491-sb
*Quo:* Phone system (calls, texts, contacts) for businesses.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/quo-ep491-sb
*CodeRabbit:* AI-powered code reviews.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/coderabbit-ep491-sb
*Fin:* AI agent for customer service.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/fin-ep491-sb
*Blitzy:* AI agent for large enterprise codebases.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/blitzy-ep491-sb
*Shopify:* Sell stuff online.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/shopify-ep491-sb
*LMNT:* Zero-sugar electrolyte drink mix.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/lmnt-ep491-sb

*OUTLINE:*
0:00 - Episode highlight
1:30 - Introduction
5:36 - OpenClaw origin story
8:55 - Mind-blowing moment
18:22 - Why OpenClaw went viral
22:19 - Self-modifying AI agent
27:04 - Name-change drama
44:15 - Moltbook saga
52:34 - OpenClaw security concerns
1:01:14 - How to code with AI agents
1:32:09 - Programming setup
1:38:52 - GPT Codex 5.3 vs Claude Opus 4.6
1:47:59 - Best AI agent for programming
2:09:59 - Life story and career advice
2:13:56 - Money and happiness
2:17:49 - Acquisition offers from OpenAI and Meta
2:34:58 - How OpenClaw works
2:46:17 - AI slop
2:52:20 - AI agents will replace 80% of apps
3:00:57 - Will AI replace programmers?
3:12:57 - Future of OpenClaw community

*PODCAST LINKS:*
- Podcast Website: https://lexfridman.com/podcast
- Apple Podcasts: https://apple.co/2lwqZIr
- Spotify: https://spoti.fi/2nEwCF8
- RSS: https://lexfridman.com/feed/podcast/
- Podcast Playlist: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLrAXtmErZgOdP_8GztsuKi9nrraNbKKp4
- Clips Channel: https://www.youtube.com/lexclips

*SOCIAL LINKS:*
- X: https://x.com/lexfridman
- Instagram: https://instagram.com/lexfridman
- TikTok: https://tiktok.com/@lexfridman
- LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/lexfridman
- Facebook: https://facebook.com/lexfridman
- Patreon: https://patreon.com/lexfridman
- Telegram: https://t.me/lexfridman
- Reddit: https://reddit.com/r/lexfridman]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Sex Life of Charles II</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/the-sex-life-of-charles-ii</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/69837a8037d752e9a34e003a/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=JaMnV-snVt9jkDxgilWc8ALlpKNsKJbBKRFpLH-1lBU" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[He had at least 14 known mistresses and a hoard of illegitimate children; Charles II's private life was as politically charged as it was scandalous. He presided over the Restoration court, a world of excess, intrigue, gambling, gossip and a lot of sex. Dan is joined by the host of the Betwixt the Sheets podcast, Dr Kate Lister, to explore the salacious side of Restoration England and examine how power, pleasure, and reputation collided at court.A warning that this episode isn't suitable for children! Produced by Mariana Des Forges and edited by Dougal Patmore.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Building the machine that builds the machine (Interview)</title><link>https://changelog.com/podcast/676</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/podcast/676/the-changelog-676.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Paul Dix joins us to discuss the InfluxDB co-founder’s journey adapting to an agentic world. Paul sent his AI coding agents on various real-world side quests and shares all his findings: what’s going to prod, what’s not, and why he’s (at least for a bit) back to coding by hand.Changelog++ members save 4 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!Namespace – Speed up your development and testing workflows using your existing tools. (Much) faster GitHub actions, Docker builds, and more. At an unbeatable price.
Tiger Data – Postgres for Developers, devices, and agents The data platform trusted by hundreds of thousands from IoT to Web3 to AI and more.
Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps close to your users — global Anycast load-balancing, zero-configuration private networking, hardware isolation, and instant WireGuard VPN connections. Push-button deployments that scale to thousands of instances. Check out the speedrun to get started in minutes.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2452 - Roger Avary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CH5JoJ_-hic</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/CH5JoJ_-hic?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:00:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Roger Avary is a director, producer, and Academy Award-winning screenwriter known for “Pulp Fiction,” which he co-wrote with Quentin Tarantino, as well as “The Rules of Attraction” and “Killing Zoe.” He is the co-host, along with Tarantino, of “The Video Archives Podcast.”

https://www.youtube.com/@videoarchivespodcast
https://www.patreon.com/videoarchives
https://www.avary.com

Perplexity: Download the app or ask Perplexity anything at https://pplx.ai/rogan.

Try ZipRecruiter FOR FREE at https://ziprecruiter.com/rogan

Visible. Live in the know. https://www.Visible.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Eleonore Stump - How Does Salvation Work?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g3B8Ef4ZSDk</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/g3B8Ef4ZSDk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:00:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Shop the Closer To Truth merch store for items like hoodies, T-shirts, mugs, and more: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

The Christian claim is that salvation is the ultimate goal of human life. But what literally is salvation and how does one obtain it? How to comprehend each element of the salvation process and the way they work together? One need not be a Christian to appreciate the philosophical conundrums.

Make a donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Eleonore Stump is an American philosopher and the Robert J. Henle Professor of Philosophy at Saint Louis University, where she has taught since 1992.

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Terrence Deacon - Philosophy of Evolutionary Cognition, Emotion, &amp; Consciousness</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xh2SncNB8vU</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Xh2SncNB8vU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:00:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Follow Closer To Truth on Instagram for daily videos, updates, and announcements: https://www.instagram.com/closertotruth/

What can evolution reveal about the developmental history of thinking and feeling? How did cognition and emotion (affect) co-develop over evolutionary time? Moreover, what can we learn from evolution about the mystery of consciousness?

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help support Closer To Truth continue making content like this: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Terrence William Deacon is an American neuroanthropologist. He taught at Harvard for eight years, relocated to Boston University in 1992, and is currently Professor of Anthropology and member of the Cognitive Science Faculty at the University of California, Berkeley.

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Software Engineering in the Age of Coding Agents: Testing, Evals, and Shipping Safely at Scale</title><link>https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/mlops/episodes/Software-Engineering-in-the-Age-of-Coding-Agents-Testing--Evals--and-Shipping-Safely-at-Scale-e3eta9q</link><author>Demetrios</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://anchor.fm/s/174cb1b8/podcast/play/115304186/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2026-1-10%2F417834561-44100-2-32c1411bf9507.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:00:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mlops.community/">Podcast - MLOps</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ is the Founding Engineer at 7AI, where he’s focused on building and scaling the company’s agentic AI-driven cybersecurity platform — developing autonomous AI agents that triage alerts, investigate threats, enrich security data, and enable end-to-end automated security operations so human teams can focus on higher-value strategic work.Software Engineering in the Age of Coding Agents: Testing, Evals, and Shipping Safely at Scale // MLOps Podcast #361 with Ereli Eran, Founding Engineer at 7AIA conversation on how AI coding agents are changing the way we build and operate production systems. We explore the practical boundaries between agentic and deterministic code, strategies for shared responsibility across models, engineering teams, and customers, and how to evaluate agent performance at scale. Topics include production quality gates, safety and cost tradeoffs, managing long-tail failures, and deployment patterns that let you ship agents with confidence.Ereli Eran is a founding engineer at 7AI, where he builds agentic AI systems for security operations and the production infrastructure that powers them. His work spans the full stack - from designing experiment frameworks for LLM-based alert investigation to architecting secure multi-tenant systems with proper authentication boundaries. Previously, he worked in data science and software engineering roles at Stripe, VMware Carbon Black, and was an early employee of Ravelin and Normalyze.~~~~~~~~ ✌️Connect With Us ✌️ ~~~~~~~[00:00] Language Sensitivity in Reasoning[00:25] Value of Claude Code[01:54] AI in Security Workflows[06:21] Agentic Systems Failures[12:50] Progressive Disclosure in Voice Agents[16:39] LLM vs Classic ML[19:44] Hybrid Approach to Fraud[25:58] Debugging with User Feedback[42:07] LLM Security Workflow[45:10] Shared Memory in Security[49:11] Common Agent Failure Modes]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2451 - Cheryl Hines</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0sMrvv53e9Y</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0sMrvv53e9Y?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:00:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Cheryl Hines is an Emmy Award-nominated actress, director, producer, and comedian. While she is best known for her role as Cheryl David on the HBO series “Curb Your Enthusiasm,” Hines has appeared in numerous films and television series over a career spanning more than 30 years, and is married to U.S. Secretary of Health and Human Services Robert F. Kennedy Jr.  Her book, “Unscripted,” is available now.

https://www.skyhorsepublishing.com/9781944824365/unscripted/

Perplexity: Download the app or ask Perplexity anything at https://pplx.ai/rogan.

Get a free welcome kit with your first subscription of AG1 at https://drinkag1.com/joerogan]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Àlex Gómez-Marín - The Science of Consciousness</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PFDCsN7QMuo</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/PFDCsN7QMuo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:00:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Contribute what you can to support Closer To Truth: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Alex Gómez-Marín is a Spanish physicist turned neuroscientist. He holds a PhD in theoretical physics and a Masters in biophysics from the University of Barcelona. He was a research fellow at the EMBL-CRG Centre for Genomic Regulation and at the Champalimaud Centre for the Unknown in Lisbon. His research spans from the origins of the arrow of time in inert systems, to the neurobiology of action-perception in living organisms such as flies, worms, mice, and humans.

Like us on Facebook for daily videos, updates, announcements, and much more: https://shorturl.at/tak4l

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Does 2+2 really equal 4?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/yqLowdJsLj4</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/yqLowdJsLj4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:31:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Is "2+2=4" the absolute truth? Philosopher of science Silvia Jonas unpacks non-naturalist metaphysics, ineffability, and what can be proved in the lab. Watch the full conversation here: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6ejqou2Dd9E]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Python 3.14 with Łukasz Langa</title><link>https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2026/02/10/python-3-14-with-lukasz-langa/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=python-3-14-with-lukasz-langa</link><author>SEDaily</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.megaphone.fm/SED4837519291.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:00:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="http://softwareengineeringdaily.com/category/all-episodes/exclusive-content/podcast/">Podcast - Software Engineering Daily</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Python 3.14 is here and continues Python’s evolution toward greater performance, scalability, and usability. The new release formally supports free-threaded, no-GIL mode, introduces template string literals, and implements deferred evaluation of type annotations. It also includes new debugging and profiling tools, along with many other features.Łukasz Langa is the CPython Developer in Residence at the Python Software Foundation, and he joins Sean Falconer to discuss the 3.14 release, the future of free threading, type system improvements, Python’s growing role in AI, and how the language continues to evolve while maintaining its commitment to backward compatibility.Sean’s been an academic, startup founder, and Googler. He has published works covering a wide range of topics from AI to quantum computing. Currently, Sean is an AI Entrepreneur in Residence at Confluent where he works on AI strategy and thought leadership. You can connect with Sean on LinkedIn.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Vouch for an open source web of trust (News)</title><link>https://changelog.com/news/180</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/news/180/changelog-news-180.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 9 Feb 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Mitchell Hashimoto’s trust management system for open source, Nicholas Carlini has a team of Claudes build a C compiler, Stephan Schwab recounts the history of attempted developer replacement, NanClaw is an alternative to OpenClaw, and Sophie Koonin can’t wrap her head around so many people going so hard on LLM-generated code.Changelog++ members save 1 minute on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ernan McMullin - Did God Create Time?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pqUIUG9gCqQ</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/pqUIUG9gCqQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 9 Feb 2026 16:01:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Like us on Facebook for daily videos, updates, announcements, and much more: https://shorturl.at/tak4l

God and time are two huge mysteries. Relating them probes the nature of God, and perhaps even the existence of God. God, in order to be Creator, must create everything other than God’s own self, which includes time. But if God is in time and experiences its passage, then how could God have created time? Also Leibniz’s question: “Why didn’t God create the world sooner?”

Wear your support for the show with a Closer To Truth merchandise purchase: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Ernan McMullin was an Irish philosopher who last served as the O’Hara Professor of Philosophy Emeritus at the University of Notre Dame. He was an internationally respected philosopher of science who has written and lectured extensively on subjects ranging from the relationship between cosmology and theology, to the role of values in understanding science, to the impact of Darwinism on Western religious thought. He is the only person to ever hold the presidency of four of the major US philosophical associations. He was an expert on the life of Galileo.

Donate to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions without the need for paywalls: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Great Famine</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/the-great-famine</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/697cccb52d4292666accaa5d/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=0hwsO299wxPW3Imzfw-l8C7-fnMkGulUKTsdzZaB7zc" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 9 Feb 2026 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In the late 19th century, Ireland suffered a potato blight that became a mass catastrophe. Today, we explore the conditions that left millions vulnerable, and assess the role of the British government in shaping the crisis.For this, we're joined by Professor Christine Kinealy, founding Director of Ireland's Great Hunger Institute at Quinnipiac University.Produced by James Hickmann and edited by Dougal Patmore.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Galen Strawson - Panpsychism: Arguing Pro and Con</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ysA2MszmRHA</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ysA2MszmRHA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 8 Feb 2026 16:01:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Shop the Closer To Truth merch store for items like hoodies, T-shirts, mugs, and more: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Panpsychism is the theory that consciousness is irreducible and exists fundamentally at the foundations of reality. Panpsychism forms include ‘micropsychism,’ where fundamental particles or fields are in some sense conscious, and ‘Cosmopsychism,’ where the entire universe is in some sense conscious. What are the arguments for and against Panpsychism like the ‘combination problem’?

Make a donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Galen John Strawson is a British analytic philosopher and literary critic who works primarily on philosophy of mind, metaphysics, John Locke, David Hume, Immanuel Kant and Friedrich Nietzsche.

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Science vs. religion?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/u6rnjOnU7yk</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/u6rnjOnU7yk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 7 Feb 2026 20:00:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Science and religions have been at odds for centuries, but are they inherently incompatible? We ask philosopher William Lane Craig, who is also a evangelical Christian, why science is so important.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Denis Noble - Philosophy of Extended Evolutionary Synthesis</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ROWcCjcQXIk</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ROWcCjcQXIk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 7 Feb 2026 16:00:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you get your podcasts: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

What is the extended evolutionary synthesis (EES) and why better? Includes multilevel selection, transgenerational epigenetic inheritance, niche construction, evolvability, and ideas from evolutionary developmental biology. Why is EES controversial?

Denis Noble CBE FRS FMedSci MAE is a British physiologist and biologist who held the Burdon Sanderson Chair of Cardiovascular Physiology at the University of Oxford from 1984 to 2004 and was appointed professor emeritus and co-director of computational physiology.

Make a donation to Closer To Truth to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions without the need for paywalls: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>It&apos;s a renaissance woman&apos;s world (Friends)</title><link>https://changelog.com/friends/127</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/friends/127/changelog--friends-127.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 6 Feb 2026 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Amal Hussein returns to tell us all about her new role at Istari, what life is like outside the web browser, how she’s helping ambitious orgs in aerospace, what the SDLC looks like in 2026, and a whole lot more. Wait, moon vacuums?!Changelog++ members get a bonus 21 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!Tiger Data – Postgres for Developers, devices, and agents The data platform trusted by hundreds of thousands from IoT to Web3 to AI and more.
Namespace – Speed up your development and testing workflows using your existing tools. (Much) faster GitHub actions, Docker builds, and more. At an unbeatable price.
NordLayer – Toggle-ready network security for modern businesses. Get an exclusive offer: up to 22% off NordLayer yearly plans plus 10% on top with the coupon code . Try it risk-free with a 14-day money-back guarantee at nordlayer.com/thechangelog]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ask Me Anything with Robert Lawrence Kuhn (Part II)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uYBiIgNUVuU</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/uYBiIgNUVuU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 6 Feb 2026 21:00:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Robert Kawrence Kuhn answers fan questions on theories of consciousness, cognitive computation, theism, determinism, and more.

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Physical AI: Teaching Machines to Understand the Real World</title><link>https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/mlops/episodes/Physical-AI-Teaching-Machines-to-Understand-the-Real-World-e3entui</link><author>Demetrios</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://anchor.fm/s/174cb1b8/podcast/play/115127698/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2026-1-6%2F417599641-44100-2-b7037fd434326.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 6 Feb 2026 19:01:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mlops.community/">Podcast - MLOps</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ is the Co-Founder and CTO at Archetype AI, working on physical AI foundation models that understand and reason over real-world sensor data.Physical AI: Teaching Machines to Understand the Real World // MLOps Podcast #360 with Nick Gillian, Co-Founder and CTO of Archetype AIAs AI moves beyond the cloud and simulation, the next frontier is Physical AI: systems that can perceive, understand, and act within real-world environments in real time. In this conversation, Nick Gillian, Co-Founder and CTO of Archetype AI, explores what it actually takes to turn raw sensor and video data into reliable, deployable intelligence.Drawing on his experience building Google’s Soli and Jacquard and now leading development of Newton, a foundational model for Physical AI, Nick discusses how real-time physical understanding changes what’s possible across safety monitoring, infrastructure, and human–machine interaction. He’ll share lessons learned translating advanced research into products that operate safely in dynamic environments, and why many organizations underestimate the challenges and opportunities of AI in the physical world.Nick Gillian, Ph.D., is Co-Founder and CTO of Archetype AI with over 15 years of experience turning advanced AI and interaction research into real-world products. At Archetype, he leads the AI and engineering teams behind Newton—a first-of-its-kind Physical AI foundational model that can perceive, understand, and reason about the physical world. Before co-founding Archetype, Nick was a Senior Staff Machine Learning Engineer at Google and a researcher at MIT, where he developed AI and ML methods for real-time sensor understanding. At Google’s Advanced Technology and Projects group, he led machine learning research that powered breakthrough products like Soli radar and Jacquard, and helped advance sensing algorithms across Pixel, Nest, and wearable devices.~~~~~~~~ ✌️Connect With Us ✌️ ~~~~~~~Timestamps:[00:00] Physical Agent Framework[00:56] Physical AI Clarification[06:53] Building a Repair Model[12:41] World Models and LLMs[17:17] Data Weighting Strategies[24:19] Data Diversity vs Quantity[38:30] R&D and Product Creation[41:22] Construction Site Data Shipping[50:33] Wrap up]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Can the eye solve the hard problem of consciousness?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/qb9Joo_U2V0</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/qb9Joo_U2V0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 6 Feb 2026 19:00:54 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Does our vision give us unique insights into a physicalist theory of consciousness? Professor Naotsugu Tsuchiya shares his research on how the cornea, the clear dome shaped part of our eye, can be used with Integrated Information Theory, one of the currently leading theories of consciousness to tackle the hard problem of consciousness.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2450 - Tommy Wood</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UPfN2G0RyQM</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/UPfN2G0RyQM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 6 Feb 2026 18:00:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Tommy Wood, PhD, is a neuroscientist and athletic performance coach. He is a host of the “Better Brain Fitness” podcast and author of “The Stimulated Mind: Future-Proof Your Brain from Dementia and Stay Sharp at Any Age,” which will be released March 24 and is available for preorder now.

https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/751292/the-stimulated-mind-by-dr-tommy-wood/
https://www.thestimulatedmind.com
https://www.betterbrain.fitness
https://www.drtommywood.com

Perplexity: Download the app or ask Perplexity anything at https://pplx.ai/rogan.

Make your sports picks with DraftKings Predictions, available in California, Florida, Texas and more. Download the DraftKings Predictions app today. Sign up using promo code ROGAN or at https://dkpred.sng.link/Ereb8/jbhu/dogs
GUS III LLC d/b/a DraftKings Predictions is a CFTC-registered Introducing Broker and NFA member. Event contract trading involves substantial risk of loss and is not suitable for everyone. 1 per new customer. Opt-in req. 100% trade match. Max. $75 issued as non-withdrawable Predictions Dollars that expire in 1 year. Ends 2/15/26 11:59 PM ET. Market availability varies. Eligibility restrictions apply. Terms: https://predictions.draftkings.com/en/promos. Sponsored by DK.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2449 - Raul Bilecky</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BvhFuEp55X0</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/BvhFuEp55X0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 5 Feb 2026 18:00:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Raul Bilecky is a researcher, explorer, and creator of the YouTube channel “Pillars of the Past.”

https://www.youtube.com/@PillarsofthePast101
https://www.patreon.com/PillarsofthePast
https://www.pillarsofthepast.com

Perplexity: Download the app or ask Perplexity anything at https://pplx.ai/rogan.

Don’t miss out on all the action this week at DraftKings! Download the DraftKings app today! Sign-up using https://dkng.co/rogan or through my promo code ROGAN.
GAMBLING PROBLEM? CALL 1-800-GAMBLER, (800) 327-5050 or visit https://gamblinghelplinema.org (MA). Call 877-8-HOPENY/text HOPENY (467369) (NY). Please Gamble Responsibly. 888-789-7777/visit https://ccpg.org (CT), or visit https://www.mdgamblinghelp.org (MD). 21+ and present in most states. (18+ DC/KY/NH/WY). Void in ONT/OR/NH. Eligibility restrictions apply. On behalf of Boot Hill Casino & Resort (KS). Pass-thru of per wager tax may apply in IL. 1 per new customer. Must register new account to receive reward Token. Must select Token BEFORE placing min. $5 bet to receive $300 in Bonus Bets if your bet wins. Min. -500 odds req. Token and Bonus Bets are single-use and non-withdrawable. Bet must settle by and Token expires 2/22/26. Bonus Bets expire in 7 days (168 hours). Stake removed from payout. Terms: https://sportsbook.draftkings.com/promos. Ends 2/15/26 at 11:59 PM ET. Sponsored by DK.

30% off + two free gifts. Visit https://ARMRA.com/ROGAN]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Airbnb’s Open-Source GraphQL Framework with Adam Miskiewicz</title><link>https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2026/02/05/airbnbs-open-source-graphql-framework-with-adam-miskiewicz/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=airbnbs-open-source-graphql-framework-with-adam-miskiewicz</link><author>SEDaily</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.megaphone.fm/SED7680215734.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 5 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="http://softwareengineeringdaily.com/category/all-episodes/exclusive-content/podcast/">Podcast - Software Engineering Daily</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Engineering teams often build microservices as their systems grow, but over time this can lead to a fragmented ecosystem with scattered data access patterns, duplicated business logic, and an uneven developer experience. A unified data graph with a consistent execution layer helps address these challenges by centralizing schema, simplifying how teams compose functionality, and reducing operational overhead while preserving performance and reliability.Viaduct is Airbnb’s open-source, data-oriented service mesh and GraphQL platform built around a single, highly connected central schema. It has played a major role in scaling Airbnb’s engineering organization.Adam Miskiewicz is a Principal Software Engineer at Airbnb and he worked on Viaduct. He joins the podcast with Gregor Vand to talk about how Viaduct originated inside Airbnb, the architectural principles that shaped it, the challenges of scaling GraphQL to millions of queries per second, and why the team decided to open-source the platform. They also discuss the future of backend development in an AI-driven world and how unified data layers may influence the next generation of engineering systems.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How Did Three Samurai Warlords Unite Japan?</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/how-did-three-samurai-warlords-unite-japan</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/6978efd39b5ca1c75cc63da2/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=vnz29xCbL3ByPsLE36M73QMOj98Uzvwm7_0Iaj4MhYw" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 5 Feb 2026 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Today, we dive into the chaotic final act of Japan’s Warring States period, and hear about the three warlords who brought it to an end. Oda Nobunaga, the ruthless innovator who shattered the status quo on the battlefield. Toyotomi Hideyoshi, the peasant-born schemer who climbed from the lowest social ranks to the very top of Japan's hierarchy. And Tokugawa Ieyasu, the patient survivor who outlasted them all and built a shogunate that would rule Japan for over 250 years.Joining us for this is Chris Harding, a cultural historian of Japan, India and East-West connections, based at the University of Edinburgh.Produced by James Hickmann and edited by Dougal Patmore.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Setting Docker Hardened Images free (Interview)</title><link>https://changelog.com/podcast/675</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/podcast/675/the-changelog-675.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 4 Feb 2026 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In May of 2025, Docker launched Hardened Images, a secure, minimal, production-ready set of images. In December, they made DHI freely available and open source to everyone who builds software. On this episode, we’re joined by Tushar Jain, EVP of Engineering at Docker to learn all about it.Changelog++ members get a bonus 6 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!Tiger Data – Postgres for Developers, devices, and agents The data platform trusted by hundreds of thousands from IoT to Web3 to AI and more.
Namespace – Speed up your development and testing workflows using your existing tools. (Much) faster GitHub actions, Docker builds, and more. At an unbeatable price.
NordLayer – Toggle-ready network security for modern businesses. Get an exclusive offer: up to 22% off NordLayer yearly plans plus 10% on top with the coupon code . Try it risk-free with a 14-day money-back guarantee at nordlayer.com/thechangelogFly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps close to your users — global Anycast load-balancing, zero-configuration private networking, hardware isolation, and instant WireGuard VPN connections. Push-button deployments that scale to thousands of instances. Check out the speedrun to get started in minutes.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2448 - Andrew Doyle</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dnon-AsWnOQ</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Dnon-AsWnOQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 4 Feb 2026 18:00:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Andrew Doyle is a writer, broadcaster, and comedian. He is the author of several books, including his most recent, “The End of Woke: How the Culture War Went Too Far and What to Expect from the Counter-Revolution.”
https://www.andrewdoyle.org

Perplexity: Download the app or ask Perplexity anything at https://pplx.ai/rogan.

Go to https://1800flowers.com/rogan to get your Double Blooms offer, buy one dozen, they’ll double it to two dozen roses free

This video is sponsored by BetterHelp. Visit https://BetterHelp.com/JRE]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2447 - Mike Benz</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MkqDA9W4Vo0</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/MkqDA9W4Vo0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 3 Feb 2026 18:00:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Mike Benz is the Executive Director of the Foundation for Freedom Online and a former official with the U.S. Department of State.
https://www.youtube.com/@MikeBenzCyberOfficial
https://www.foundationforfreedomonline.com

Perplexity: Download the app or ask Perplexity anything at https://pplx.ai/rogan.

Don’t miss out on all the action this week at DraftKings! Download the DraftKings app today! Sign-up using https://dkng.co/rogan or through my promo code ROGAN.
GAMBLING PROBLEM? CALL 1-800-GAMBLER, (800) 327-5050 or visit https://gamblinghelplinema.org (MA). Call 877-8-HOPENY/text HOPENY (467369) (NY). Please Gamble Responsibly. 888-789-7777/visit https://ccpg.org (CT), or visit https://www.mdgamblinghelp.org (MD). 21+ and present in most states. (18+ DC/KY/NH/WY). Void in ONT/OR/NH. Eligibility restrictions apply. On behalf of Boot Hill Casino & Resort (KS). Pass-thru of per wager tax may apply in IL. 1 per new customer. Must register new account to receive reward Token. Must select Token BEFORE placing min. $5 bet to receive $300 in Bonus Bets if your bet wins. Min. -500 odds req. Token and Bonus Bets are single-use and non-withdrawable. Bet must settle by and Token expires 2/22/26. Bonus Bets expire in 7 days (168 hours). Stake removed from payout. Terms: https://sportsbook.draftkings.com/promos. Ends 2/15/26 at 11:59 PM ET. Sponsored by DK.

Visit https://squarespace.com/ROGAN to save 10% off your first purchase of a website or domain.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Speed and Scale: How Today&apos;s AI Datacenters Are Operating Through Hypergrowth</title><link>https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/mlops/episodes/Speed-and-Scale-How-Todays-AI-Datacenters-Are-Operating-Through-Hypergrowth-e3ej6ks</link><author>Demetrios</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://anchor.fm/s/174cb1b8/podcast/play/114972764/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2026-1-3%2F417394904-44100-2-451b18cae6d3.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 3 Feb 2026 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mlops.community/">Podcast - MLOps</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ is the CEO at NetBox Labs, working on turning NetBox into the system of record and automation backbone for modern and AI-driven infrastructure.Speed and Scale: How Today's AI Datacenters Are Operating Through Hypergrowth // MLOps Podcast #359 with Kris Beevers, CEO of NetBox LabsHundreds of neocloud operators and "AI Factory" builders have emerged to serve the insatiable demand for AI infrastructure. These teams are compressing the design, build, deploy, operate, scale cycle of their infrastructures down to months, while managing massive footprints with lean teams. How? By applying modern intent-driven infrastructure automation principles to greenfield deployments. We'll explore how these teams carry design intent through to production, and how operating and automating around consistent infrastructure data is compressing "time to first train".Kris Beevers is the Co-founder and CEO of NetBox Labs. NetBox is used by nearly every Neocloud and AI datacenter to manage their networks and infrastructure. Kris is an engineer at heart and by background, and loves the leverage infrastructure innovation creates to accelerate technology and empower engineers to do their best work. A serial entrepreneur, Kris has founded and helped lead multiple other successful businesses in the internet and network infrastructure. Most recently, he co-founded and led NS1, which was acquired by IBM in 2023. He holds a Ph.D. in Computer Science from Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute and is based in New Jersey.~~~~~~~~ ✌️Connect With Us ✌️ ~~~~~~~[00:00] Observability and Delta Analysis[00:26] New World Exploration[04:06] Bottlenecks in AI Infrastructure[13:37] Data Center Optimization Challenges[19:58] Tech Stack Breakdown[25:26] Data Center Design Principles[31:32] Constraints and Automation in Design[40:00] Complexity in Data Centers[45:02] GPU Cloud Landscape[50:24] Data Centers in Containers[57:45] Observability Beyond Software[1:04:43] Tighter Integrations vs NetBox]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>SED News: Apple Bets on Gemini, Google’s AI Advantage, and the Talent Arms Race</title><link>https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2026/02/03/sed-news-apple-bets-on-gemini-googles-ai-advantage-and-the-talent-arms-race/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=sed-news-apple-bets-on-gemini-googles-ai-advantage-and-the-talent-arms-race</link><author>SEDaily</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.megaphone.fm/SED5113011729.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 3 Feb 2026 10:00:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="http://softwareengineeringdaily.com/category/all-episodes/exclusive-content/podcast/">Podcast - Software Engineering Daily</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[SED News is a monthly podcast from Software Engineering Daily where hosts Gregor Vand and Sean Falconer unpack the biggest stories shaping software engineering, Silicon Valley, and the broader tech industry.In this episode, they cover Starlink’s rapid rollout of free, high-speed in-flight internet, Tesla’s move to deprecate Autopilot in favor of full self-driving, and Apple’s reported decision to power Siri with Google’s Gemini models. They also discuss Meta’s $2B acquisition of Manus, Waymo’s growing pains as autonomous vehicles scale, and the competitive shockwaves triggered by Google’s advances in custom AI hardware.Gregor and Sean then dive deep into the state of the tech job market, examining OpenAI’s decision to eliminate vesting cliffs, the escalating war for elite AI talent, and what recent layoffs really say about the future of software engineering. They explore how AI coding tools are reshaping the balance between junior and senior engineers, why fundamentals still matter, and what developers should focus on heading into 2026.Finally, they highlight standout threads from Hacker News, including Doom running on wireless earbuds, the enduring appeal of wildly over-engineered side projects, and why hacking for fun still matters in an age of industrial-scale AI.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The tech monoculture is finally breaking (News)</title><link>https://changelog.com/news/179</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/news/179/changelog-news-179.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 2 Feb 2026 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Jason Willems believes the tech monoculture is finally breaking, Don Ho shares some bad Notepad++ news, Tailscale’s Avery Pennarun pens a great downtime apology, Milan Milanović explains why you can only code 4 hours per day, and Addy Osmani on managing comprehension debt when leaning on AI to code.Changelog++ members save 1 minute on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!Tiger Data – Postgres for Developers, devices, and agents The data platform trusted by hundreds of thousands from IoT to Web3 to AI and more.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Whaling</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/whaling</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/697ca97065c54ec919934339/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=8V6HMTZXcJrANeg3vQ5Un-Wb20Aqv13is2tTc8k_MhE" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 2 Feb 2026 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The history of whaling is complicated. At its height in the 18th and 19th centuries, whaling was a global enterprise built on perilous voyages, long seasons at sea, and a fierce chase for oil and baleen that illuminated streets and homes and lubricated the industrial revolution. In doing so, obsessed nations like Britain, Norway and America hounded whale populations to the brink, decimating populations and altering marine ecosystems forever. But it's important to remember that this industry also has a rich social history. Whaling sustained communities across the globe, providing work, culture and a crucial way of life for working people in coastal regions and on remote islands like Shetland off the coast of Scotland. In this episode, Dan heads to Dundee, once a hub of the whaling industry, to explore both the devastating ecological impact and the rich human story to give us a fuller understanding of the history of whaling. He speaks to the curators at the South Georgia Museum, Jayne Pierce and Helen Balfour, as well as Richard Sabin from the Natural History Museum and also one of Shetland's last remaining whalers, Gibby Fraser. You can explore more at https://whalersmemorybank.sgmuseum.gs/ to read through testimonies from other whalers, see incredible archive images and learn more about whales in the Arctic and Antarctic. Produced by Mariana Des Forges and edited by Dougal Patmore]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>State of AI in 2026: LLMs, Coding, Scaling Laws, China, Agents, GPUs, AGI | Lex Fridman Podcast #490</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EV7WhVT270Q</link><author>Lex Fridman</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EV7WhVT270Q?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 22:33:33 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSHZKyawb77ixDdsGog4iWA">Podcast - Lex Fridman</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Nathan Lambert and Sebastian Raschka are machine learning researchers, engineers, and educators. Nathan is the post-training lead at the Allen Institute for AI (Ai2) and the author of The RLHF Book. Sebastian Raschka is the author of Build a Large Language Model (From Scratch) and Build a Reasoning Model (From Scratch).
Thank you for listening ❤ Check out our sponsors: https://lexfridman.com/sponsors/ep490-sb
See below for timestamps, transcript, and to give feedback, submit questions, contact Lex, etc.

*Transcript:*
https://lexfridman.com/ai-sota-2026-transcript

*Correction:*
Here's an updated image listing a collection of recent open & closed AI models with some improvements & fixes:
https://lexfridman.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/ai_models_2025.png

*CONTACT LEX:*
*Feedback* - give feedback to Lex: https://lexfridman.com/survey
*AMA* - submit questions, videos or call-in: https://lexfridman.com/ama
*Hiring* - join our team: https://lexfridman.com/hiring
*Other* - other ways to get in touch: https://lexfridman.com/contact

*EPISODE LINKS:*
Nathan's X: https://x.com/natolambert
Nathan's Blog: https://interconnects.ai
Nathan's Website: https://natolambert.com
Nathan's YouTube: https://youtube.com/@natolambert
Nathan's GitHub: https://github.com/natolambert
Nathan's Book: https://rlhfbook.com
Sebastian's X: https://x.com/rasbt
Sebastian's Blog: https://magazine.sebastianraschka.com
Sebastian's Website: https://sebastianraschka.com
Sebastian's YouTube: https://youtube.com/@SebastianRaschka
Sebastian's GitHub: https://github.com/rasbt
Sebastian's Books:
Build a Large Language Model (From Scratch): https://manning.com/books/build-a-large-language-model-from-scratch
Build a Reasoning Model (From Scratch): https://manning.com/books/build-a-reasoning-model-from-scratch

*SPONSORS:*
To support this podcast, check out our sponsors & get discounts:
*Box:* Intelligent content management platform.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/box-ep490-sb
*Quo:* Phone system (calls, texts, contacts) for businesses.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/quo-ep490-sb
*UPLIFT Desk:* Standing desks and office ergonomics.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/uplift_desk-ep490-sb
*Fin:* AI agent for customer service.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/fin-ep490-sb
*Shopify:* Sell stuff online.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/shopify-ep490-sb
*CodeRabbit:* AI-powered code reviews.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/coderabbit-ep490-sb
*LMNT:* Zero-sugar electrolyte drink mix.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/lmnt-ep490-sb
*Perplexity:* AI-powered answer engine.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/perplexity-ep490-sb

*OUTLINE:*
0:00 - Introduction
1:57 - China vs US: Who wins the AI race?
10:38 - ChatGPT vs Claude vs Gemini vs Grok: Who is winning?
21:38 - Best AI for coding
28:29 - Open Source vs Closed Source LLMs
40:08 - Transformers: Evolution of LLMs since 2019
48:05 - AI Scaling Laws: Are they dead or still holding?
1:04:12 - How AI is trained: Pre-training, Mid-training, and Post-training
1:37:18 - Post-training explained: Exciting new research directions in LLMs
1:58:11 - Advice for beginners on how to get into AI development & research
2:21:03 - Work culture in AI (72+ hour weeks)
2:24:49 - Silicon Valley bubble
2:28:46 - Text diffusion models and other new research directions
2:34:28 - Tool use
2:38:44 - Continual learning
2:44:06 - Long context
2:50:21 - Robotics
2:59:31 - Timeline to AGI
3:06:47 - Will AI replace programmers?
3:25:18 - Is the dream of AGI dying?
3:32:07 - How AI will make money?
3:36:29 - Big acquisitions in 2026
3:41:01 - Future of OpenAI, Anthropic, Google DeepMind, xAI, Meta
3:53:35 - Manhattan Project for AI
4:00:10 - Future of NVIDIA, GPUs, and AI compute clusters
4:08:15 - Future of human civilization

*PODCAST LINKS:*
- Podcast Website: https://lexfridman.com/podcast
- Apple Podcasts: https://apple.co/2lwqZIr
- Spotify: https://spoti.fi/2nEwCF8
- RSS: https://lexfridman.com/feed/podcast/
- Podcast Playlist: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLrAXtmErZgOdP_8GztsuKi9nrraNbKKp4
- Clips Channel: https://www.youtube.com/lexclips

*SOCIAL LINKS:*
- X: https://x.com/lexfridman
- Instagram: https://instagram.com/lexfridman
- TikTok: https://tiktok.com/@lexfridman
- LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/lexfridman
- Facebook: https://facebook.com/lexfridman
- Patreon: https://patreon.com/lexfridman
- Telegram: https://t.me/lexfridman
- Reddit: https://reddit.com/r/lexfridman]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2446 - Greg Fitzsimmons</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IbhDeUcZ_iw</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/IbhDeUcZ_iw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 19:00:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greg Fitzsimmons is a comedian, actor, and writer, host of “Fitzdog Radio,” and co-host of “Sunday Papers” and “Childish.” He will be touring in 2026.

https://www.youtube.com/@GregFitzsimmonsComedy
https://www.sundaypapers.net
https://www.childishpod.com
https://www.gregfitzsimmons.com

Perplexity: Download the app or ask Perplexity anything at https://pplx.ai/rogan.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Natural born SaaS killers (Friends)</title><link>https://changelog.com/friends/126</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/friends/126/changelog--friends-126.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[We discuss the buzz around Clawdbot / MoltBot / OpenClaw, how app subscriptions are turning into weekend hacking projects, why SaaS stocks are crashing on Wall Street, and what it all means.Changelog++ members save 5 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!Tiger Data – Postgres for Developers, devices, and agents The data platform trusted by hundreds of thousands from IoT to Web3 to AI and more.
Namespace – Speed up your development and testing workflows using your existing tools. (Much) faster GitHub actions, Docker builds, and more. At an unbeatable price.
Squarespace – A website makes it real! Use code CHANGELOG to save 10% on your first website purchase.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2445 - Bert Kreischer</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gYcuTY7tnvk</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/gYcuTY7tnvk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 18:00:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Bert Kreischer is a comedian, actor, host of “The Bertcast” and “Something’s Burning,” and co-host of “2 Bears, 1 Cave” with Tom Segura. His new show, “Free Bert,” is streaming on Netflix. He will be touring in 2026 with the “Permission to Party” tour.

https://www.netflix.com/title/81696123
https://www.youtube.com/@bertkreischer
https://www.ymhstudios.com/2bears/
https://www.bertyboyproductions.com
https://www.bertbertbert.com

Perplexity: Download the app or ask Perplexity anything at https://pplx.ai/rogan.

Get a free welcome kit with your first subscription of AG1 at https://drinkag1.com/joerogan]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Securing npm is table stakes (Interview)</title><link>https://changelog.com/podcast/674</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/podcast/674/the-changelog-674.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[As the creator and long-time maintainer of ESLint, Nicholas Zakas is well-positioned to criticize GitHub’s recent response to npm’s insecurity. He found the response insufficient, and has other ideas on how GitHub could secure npm better. On this episode, Nicholas details these ideas, paints a bleak picture of npm alternatives like JSR, and shares our frustration that such a critical piece of internet infrastructure feels neglected.Changelog++ members save 6 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!Namespace – Speed up your development and testing workflows using your existing tools. (Much) faster GitHub actions, Docker builds, and more. At an unbeatable price.
Tiger Data – Postgres for Developers, devices, and agents The data platform trusted by hundreds of thousands from IoT to Web3 to AI and more.
Squarespace – A website makes it real! Use code CHANGELOG to save 10% on your first website purchase.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>OpenAI and Codex with Thibault Sottiaux and Ed Bayes</title><link>https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2026/01/29/openai-and-codex-with-thibault-sottiaux-and-ed-bayes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=openai-and-codex-with-thibault-sottiaux-and-ed-bayes</link><author>SEDaily</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.megaphone.fm/SED1679308715.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 10:00:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="http://softwareengineeringdaily.com/category/all-episodes/exclusive-content/podcast/">Podcast - Software Engineering Daily</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[AI coding agents are rapidly reshaping how software is built, reviewed, and maintained. As large language model capabilities continue to increase, the bottleneck in software development is shifting away from code generation toward planning, review, deployment, and coordination. This shift is driving a new class of agentic systems that operate inside constrained environments, reason over long time horizons, and integrate across tools like IDEs, version control systems, and issue trackers.OpenAI is at the forefront of AI research and product development. In 2025, the company released Codex, which is an agentic coding system designed to work safely inside sandboxed environments while collaborating across the modern software development stack.Thibault Sottiaux is the Codex engineering lead and Ed Bayes is the Codex product designer. In this episode, they join Kevin Ball to discuss how Codex is built, the co-evolution of models and harnesses, multi-agent futures, Codex’s open-source CLI, model specialization, latency and performance considerations, and much more.Kevin Ball or KBall, is the vice president of engineering at Mento and an independent coach for engineers and engineering leaders. He co-founded and served as CTO for two companies, founded the San Diego JavaScript meetup, and organizes the AI inaction discussion group through Latent Space.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joan of Arc</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/joan-of-arc</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/6971f886ad93e7a4317aa74a/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=FIKvpUsrJoi-pK8STGu19qg_j6Bl-NRUzy2YcdYsDXc" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Teenage peasant, visionary commander, convicted heretic, national saint - Joan of Arc's life reads like a legend. Today, Dan digs past that legend to understand who Joan really was, and why her story still provokes devotion, debate and reinvention 6 centuries later.Produced by Mariana Des Forges and edited by Dougal Patmore.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2444 - Andrew Wilson</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0-Jalhl4CEE</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0-Jalhl4CEE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:00:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Andrew Wilson has participated in thousands of debates on political, cultural, and religious topics. He is the host of “The Crucible” and proprietor of its associated online school, Debate University.

https://www.youtube.com/@The_Crucible
https://www.rumble.com/c/TheCrucible
https://www.thecrucible.video
https://www.debateuniversity.com

Perplexity: Download the app or ask Perplexity anything at https://pplx.ai/rogan.

Don’t miss out on all the action this week at DraftKings! Download the DraftKings app today! Sign-up using https://dkng.co/rogan or through my promo code ROGAN.
GAMBLING PROBLEM? CALL 1-800-GAMBLER, (800) 327-5050 or visit https://gamblinghelplinema.org (MA). Call 877-8-HOPENY/text HOPENY (467369) (NY). Please Gamble Responsibly. 888-789-7777/visit https://ccpg.org (CT), or visit https://www.mdgamblinghelp.org (MD). 21+ and present in most states. (18+ DC/KY/NH/WY). Void in ONT/OR/NH. Eligibility restrictions apply. On behalf of Boot Hill Casino & Resort (KS). Pass-thru of per wager tax may apply in IL. 1 per new customer. Must register new account to receive reward Token. Must select Token BEFORE placing min. $5 bet to receive $300 in Bonus Bets if your bet wins. Min. -500 odds req. Token and Bonus Bets are single-use and non-withdrawable. Bet must settle by and Token expires 2/22/26. Bonus Bets expire in 7 days (168 hours). Stake removed from payout. Terms: https://sportsbook.draftkings.com/promos. Ends 2/15/26 at 11:59 PM ET. Sponsored by DK.]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>